字幕由SSK字幕組傾情譯制
僅供學習，勿用於商，轉載請註明出處，版權歸片方所有
- 翻譯 Bunny 洛貍 張小明 九月 vyan Levi -
- 校對 Bunny -
- 壓制 HHJIE  特效 邦尼 -
- 總監  邦尼兔 -
歡迎關注新浪微博@SSK字幕組
瘋狂動物城
恐懼 背叛 血腥
Fear. Treachery. Bloodlust.
幾千年前
Thousands of years ago...
這些就是支配著我們世界的力量
these were the forces that ruled our world.
一個弱肉強食的世界
A world where prey were scared of predators.
這些食肉動物有著
And predators had an uncontrollable...
殺戮 襲擊等
biological urge...
不可遏制的生物本能
to maim, and maul, and...
血流如注 鮮血噴涌 血流成河
Blood! Blood! Blood!
然後 一命呼嗚
And death.
那時 世界分為兩個陣營
Back then, the world was divided in two.
兇猛的食肉動物
Vicious predator...
溫順的食草動物
or meek prey.
兇猛的食肉動物  溫順的食草動物
但是隨著時間的推移 我們進化了
But over time, we evolved.
並且擺脫了我們原始的野蠻天性
And moved beyond our primitive, savage ways.
現在食肉動物和食草動物和諧共處
Now, predator and prey live in harmony.
每一個年輕的小動物都有了大量的機遇
And every young mammal has multitudinous opportunities.
是的
Yeah.
我不用再躲在羊群中
I don't have to cower in a herd anymore.
並且 我還可以成為一個宇航員
Instead, I can be an astronaut.
我不用再做一個孤單的狩獵者了
I don't have to be a lonely hunter anymore.
現在我可以追捕偷稅漏稅行為
Today, I can hunt for tax exemptions.
我要成為一名精算師
I'm gonna be an actuary!
我可以讓世界變得更美好
And I can make the world a better place.
我將會成為
I am going to be...
一名警察
A police officer!
兔子警察
Bunny cop?
那是我聽過的最蠢的事情
That is the most stupidest thing I ever heard.
這對於思想狹隘的人來說也許是不可能的
It may seem impossible to small minds...
我說你呢 吉迪恩·格雷
I'm looking at you, Gideon Grey.
但是 僅211英里之外
But, just 211 miles away...
坐落著一個偉大的城市 動物城
stands the great city of Zootopia!
我們的祖先在那裏首次簽訂了和平條約
Where our ancestors first joined together in peace...
並且宣告 每個人皆有無限可能
and declared that anyone can be anything!
謝謝大家 晚安
Thank you and good night!
朱迪 你有沒有想過我和你媽媽
Judy, you ever wonder how your mom and me...
為什麼生活得這麼愉快
got to be so darn happy?
沒有
Nope.
因為我們放棄了我們的夢想 然後安定下來 對吧 邦尼
Well, we gave up on our dreams and we settled. Right, Bon?
恩 沒錯 就是這樣 斯圖 我們很安定呢
Oh, yes, that's right, Stu. We settled hard.
你看 這就是知足的好處 朱迪
See, that's the beauty of complacency, Jude.
如果你不嘗試新事物 你就永遠不會失敗
If you don't try anything new, you'll never fail.
實際上 我就喜歡嘗試
I like trying actually.
親愛的 你爸爸的意思是
What you father means, hon...
即使對你來說 要成為一名警察
is it's gonna be difficult...
也會很困難 甚至不可能
impossible even, for you to become a police officer.
好吧 從來沒有過兔子當警察
Right. There's never been a bunny cop.
-沒有過 -兔子們做不來這一行
- No. - Bunnies don't do that.
-從來沒有 -從來沒有
- Never. - Never.
噢 那我就成為第一個吧
Oh. Then, I guess I'll have to be the first one.
因為我要把這個世界
Because I am gonna make...
變得更美好
the world a better place.
或者 你知道的
Or, uh, heck, you know, you want to talk...
想讓世界變得更美好
about making the world a better place...
沒有比種胡蘿蔔更好的實現辦法了
no better way to do it than becoming a carrot farmer.
沒錯 你的爸爸 我
Yes! Your dad, me...
你的二百七十五個兄弟姐妹
your 275 brothers and sisters.
-我們在改變世界 -沒錯
- We're changing the world! - Yeah.
-一個一個蘿蔔來 -完全贊同
- One carrot at a time. - Amen to that.
種胡蘿蔔是一個高尚的職業
Carrot farming is a noble profession.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
把種子放進地裏
Just putting the seeds in the ground.
和土壤融在一起 再用泥土掩蓋
Ah, at one with the soil. Just getting covered in dirt.
你會明白的 親愛的
You get it, honey.
擁有夢想是一件很棒的事情
It's great to have dreams.
當然 只要你不過分相信它
Yeah. Just as long as you don't...
過分相信它
believe in them too much.
她又跑哪去了
Where'd the heck she go?
現在就把你的票給我
Give me your tickets right now...
否則我就要狠狠地踢你的
or I'm gonna kick your...
-小羊屁股 -嗷
- meek little sheep butt. - Ow!
住手 吉迪恩
Cut it out, Gideon!
咩 咩 你想幹什麼 哭嗎
Baa! Baa! What are you gonna do? Cry?
嘿 你聽見她說的話了 住手
Hey! You heard her. Cut it out.
戲服不錯啊 兔崽子
Nice costume, loser.
你以為你生活在什麼瘋狂的世界
What crazy world are you living in...
讓你覺得一個兔子也能當警察
where you think a bunny could be a cop?
乖乖地把我朋友的票還回來
Kindly return my friend's tickets.
來拿啊
Come and get them.
但是當心了 因為我是一隻狐貍
But watch out, because I'm a fox...
而且像你那可笑的舞台劇上說的一樣
and like you said in your dumb little stage play...
我們食肉動物過去是吃食草動物的
us predators used to eat prey.
而且那殺手的天性還存在於我們的DANA裏
And that killer instinct is still in our "Dunnah."
呃 我很確定那個念DNA
Uh, I'm pretty much sure it's pronounced "DNA."
我知道念什麼 特拉維斯
Don't tell me what I know, Travis.
你嚇不到我的 吉迪恩
You don't scare me, Gideon.
你現在害怕了嗎
You scared now?
看她那抽搐的兔鼻子
Look at her nose twitch!
她很害怕
She is scared!
哭吧 小兔寶寶
Cry little baby bunny.
哭吧
Cry, Cry...
噢 你就是不知道什麼時候放棄 是吧
Oh, you don't know when to quit, do you?
我希望你記住這個時刻
I want you to remember this moment...
你不過就是一隻
the next time you think...
種胡蘿蔔的蠢兔子 除此之外
you will ever be anything more than just a stupid...
你什麼都幹不了
carrot-farming, dumb bunny.
看起來傷的好嚴重
That looks bad.
你還好嗎 朱迪
Are you okay, Judy?
沒事 我還好 不要緊的
Yeah. Yeah, I'm okay.
-給你 -噢
- Here you go. - Oh!
哇噢 你搶回了我們的票
Wow! You got our tickets!
你真棒 朱迪
You're awesome, Judy!
沒錯 那個吉迪恩·格雷根本就是胡說八道
Yeah, that Gideon Grey doesn't know what he's talking about.
其實 有一件事他說對了
Well, he was right about one thing.
我不知道什麼時候放棄
I don't know when to quit.
動物城警察學校
聽著 學員們
Listen up, cadets.
動物城內有十二個
Zootopia has 12 unique...
十五年後
獨特的生態系統
ecosystems within its city limits.
冰原鎮
Tundratown...
撒哈拉廣場
Sahara Square...
雨林區 等等等等
Rainforest District, to name a few.
你們入職之前
You're gonna have to master all of them...
必須要掌握所有的情況 否則會怎樣呢
before you hit the streets, or guess what?
你們會掛掉
You'll be dead!
灼熱沙塵暴
Scorching sandstorm!
鄉巴佬兔子 你掛了
You're dead, Bunny Bumpkin!
千尺大瀑布
1,000-foot fall!
哇噢
Whoa!
吃胡蘿蔔的 你掛了
You're dead, Carrot Face!
冰凍高牆
Frigid ice wall!
嗚呼
Whoop!
你掛了 農場妹
You're dead, Farm Girl!
重量級罪犯
Enormous criminal.
你掛了 掛了 掛了 掛了
You're dead. Dead, dead, dead!
哇噢
Whoa...
掉進廁所
Filthy toilet!
你掛了 毛屁股
You're dead, Fluff Butt.
放棄回家吧 茸茸兔
Just quit and go home, fuzzy bunny!
從來沒有過兔子當警察
There's never been a bunny cop.
-從來沒有 -從來沒有
- Never. - Never.
你不過就是一隻種胡蘿蔔的蠢兔子
Just a stupid, carrot-farming dumb bunny.
作為動物城的市長 我自豪地宣佈
As mayor of Zootopia, I am proud to announce...
我的哺乳動物招募項目
that my Mammal inclusion Initiative has produced...
已經成功地培養出了第一批警校畢業生
its first police academy graduate.
畢業生代表
Valedictorian of her class...
動物城警局有史以來第一個兔子警官
ZPD's very first rabbit officer...
朱迪·霍普斯
Judy Hopps.
噢 天哪
Oh, gosh.
羊市長助理 她的警徽
Assistant Mayor Bellwether, her badge.
-噢 是的 是的 -謝謝
- Oh, yes. Right! - Thank you.
耶 朱迪
Yay, Judy!
朱迪
Judy.
我很榮幸地正式分配你去
it is my great privilege to officially assign you...
動物城的中心
to the heart of Zootopia:
轄區一區
Precinct One.
市中心
City Center.
恭喜你 霍普斯警官
Congratulations, Officer Hopps.
我不會讓你失望的
I won't let you down.
這是我從小到大的夢想
This has been my dream since I was a kid.
對我們小個頭來說這真是相當自豪的一天
It's a real proud day for us little guys.
羊市長助理 讓一下 好嗎 來
Bellwether, make room, will you? Come on.
好了 霍普斯警官 笑燦爛點吧
Okay, Officer Hopps. Let's see those teeth!
-霍普斯警官 看這裏 -請看這邊
- Officer Hopps, right here! - Look this way please!
不要動 微笑
Hold still. Smile!
祝你好運  朱迪
我們真為你感到驕傲 朱迪
We're real proud of you, Judy.
沒錯 也很害怕
Yeah. Scared, too.
-是啊 -真的 就是那種
- Yes. - Really, it's kind of...
又驕傲又害怕
a proud-scared combo.
我是說 動物城 那麼遠 那麼大一個城市
I mean, Zootopia. So far away. Such a big city.
爸爸媽媽
Guys...
我這輩子都在等這一天
I've been working for this my whole life.
我們知道 我們只是
We know. And we're just...
有一點為你興奮 但也很害怕
a little excited for you, but terrified.
我們唯一應該恐懼的是恐懼本身
The only thing we have to fear is fear itself.
還有熊 我們也要害怕熊
And also bears. We have bears to fear, too.
更別說獅子 還有狼
Say nothing of lions and wolves.
-狼？-黃鼠狼
- Wolves? - Weasels.
你還和黃鼠狼打牌呢
You play cribbage with a weasel.
是啊 他總是出老千
Yeah. And he cheats like there's no tomorrow.
你知道嗎 食肉動物
You know what, pretty much...
大多都那樣 而且動物城裏到處都是
all predators. And Zootopia's full of them.
噢 斯圖
Oh, Stu.
狐貍是最壞的
And foxes are the worst.
實際上 你爸說的話有一定道理
Actually, your father does have a point there.
這是他們的天性
It's in their biology.
記得吉迪恩·格雷嗎
Remember what happened with Gideon Grey?
那時我九歲
When I was nine.
吉迪恩·格雷是個混蛋 而且恰好是個狐貍
Gideon Grey was a jerk who happened to be a fox.
我知道很多兔子也是混蛋
I know plenty of bunnies who are jerks.
當然了 我們也知道 毋庸置疑 但是以防萬一
Sure, we all do. Absolutely. But just in case...
我們給你做了一個
we made you a little care...
-保命包裹給你帶著 -嗯哼
- package to take with you. - Mmm-hmm.
我還放了一些零食在裏面
And I put some snacks in there.
-這是懾狐小喇叭 -沒錯 帶著它
- This is fox deterrent. - Yeah, that's safe...
-很安全 -這是防狐噴霧
- to have that. Okay. - This is fox repellent.
小喇叭和噴霧
The deterrent and the repellent...
-這就萬事俱備了 -來看看這個
- that's all she needs. - Check this out!
噢 天吶
Oh, for goodness sake.
她不需要狐貍電擊器 斯圖
She has no need for a fox Taser, Stu.
噢 得了吧 狐貍電槍最實用了
Oh, come on. When is there not a need for a fox Taser?
好吧 行 我會帶上這個 你們不要再說了
Okay, look! I will take this, to make you stop talking.
太棒了 雙贏的結果
Terrific! Everyone wins!
動物城特快列車 到站了
Arriving, Zootopia Express.
好啦 要走啦 拜拜
Okay, gotta go! Bye!
拜 朱迪
Bye, Judy!
嗯
Mmm.
我愛你們
I love you guys.
我們也愛你
Love you, too.
噢 天哪 我要哭了
Oh, cripes, here come the waterworks.
噢 斯圖 振作一點
Oh, Stu, pull it together.
再見了大家
Bye, everybody!
-再見 朱迪 -再見 朱迪
- Bye-bye, Judy! - Bye, Judy!
我愛你
I love you!
拜拜
Bye! Bye!
再見
Good bye!
你現正離開兔窩鎮
人口數
♪ Gazelle - Try Everything
♪ 噢噢噢噢噢 ♪
♪ Oh oh oh oh ooh ♪
♪ 今夜我搞砸了 又一次落敗 ♪
♪ I messed up tonight I lost another fight ♪
♪ 再次深陷困境 那就重新再來 ♪
♪ I still mess up but I'll just start again ♪
♪ 我一路磕碰 我一路跌撞 ♪
♪ I keep falling down I keep on hitting the ground ♪
♪ 我總能重新站起 迎接嶄新未來 ♪
♪ I always get up now to see what's next ♪
♪ 鳥兒也會受傷 跌落天際 卻重新展翅 ♪
♪ Birds don't just fly They fall down and get up ♪
♪ 不經歷失敗 怎懂成功的意義 ♪
♪ Nobody learns without getting it wrong ♪
♪ 絕不輕易屈服 絕不輕言放棄 ♪
♪ I won't give up, no I won't give in ♪
♪ 直至抵達終點 我會繼續前進 ♪
♪ Till I reach the end And then I'll start again ♪
♪ 我的步履不停 我想要嘗遍世間新奇 ♪
♪ No I won't leave I wanna try everything ♪
♪ 即便注定失敗 我也想要竭盡全力 ♪
♪ I wanna try even though I could fail ♪
♪ 絕不輕易屈服 絕不輕言放棄 ♪
♪ I won't give up, no I won't give in ♪
♪ 直至抵達終點 我會繼續前進 ♪
♪ Till I reach the end And then I'll start again ♪
♪ 我的步履不停 我想要嘗遍世間新奇 ♪
♪ No I won't leave I wanna try everything ♪
♪ 即便注定失敗 我也想要竭盡全力 ♪
♪ I wanna try even though I could fail ♪
♪ 噢噢噢噢噢 嘗遍世間新奇 ♪
♪ Oh oh oh oh ooh Try everything ♪
♪ 噢噢噢噢噢 ♪
♪ Oh oh oh oh ooh ♪
♪ 前路崎嶇 屢戰屢敗 我心不息 ♪
♪ I'll keep on making those new mistakes ♪
♪ 屢戰屢敗 屢敗屢戰 我心不息 ♪
♪ I'll keep on making them every day ♪
♪ 大不了再接再厲 ♪
♪ Those new mistakes ♪
♪ 噢噢噢噢噢 嘗遍世間新奇 ♪
♪ Oh oh oh oh ooh Try everything ♪
♪ 噢噢噢噢噢 ♪
♪ Oh oh oh oh ooh ♪
♪ 嘗遍世間新奇 ♪
♪ Try everything ♪
我是夏奇羊 歡迎來到動物城
I'm Gazelle. Welcome to Zootopia.
歡迎來到豪華穿山甲大酒店
Welcome to the Grand Pangolin Arms.
魅力奢華公寓
Luxury apartments with charm.
每月一次免費除虱
Complimentary delousing once a month.
別弄丟鑰匙
Don't lose your key.
謝謝你
Thank you.
噢 嗨 我是朱迪 你們的新鄰居
Oh, hi! I'm Judy, your new neighbor.
是嗎 我們很吵
Yeah? Well, we're loud.
別指望我們為此道歉
Don't expect us to apologize for it.
油膩的牆壁
Greasy walls.
嘿 閉嘴
Hey, shut up!
搖擺的床
Rickety bed.
-你閉嘴 -你才閉嘴
- You shut up! - You shut up!
閉嘴好嗎
Will you shut up?
瘋狂的鄰居
Crazy neighbors.
我都叫你閉嘴了
I said, "Shut up!"
我愛死這裏啦
I love it!
閉上你的嘴 閉嘴
Shut your mouth, shut up.
閉嘴
Shut up!
防狐噴霧
拜託
Come on!
他先露出牙齒的
He bared his teeth first!
打擾一下
Excuse me.
在下面
Down here.
你好
Hi.
天 啦 嚕
O-M-Goodness!
他們真的雇了一隻兔子
They really did hire a bunny! What!
我要告訴你 你比我想像中
I gotta tell you, you are even cuter...
還要可愛
than I thought you'd be!
噢 呃 你可能不知道
Oh, ah. You probably didn't know...
一隻兔子可以說另一隻兔子 可愛
but a bunny can call another bunny "Cute"...
但其他動物這麼說
but when other animals do it...
就有一點...
it's a little...
噢 真抱歉 我是本傑明·豹豪澤
I am so sorry! Me, Benjamin Clawhauser...
大家都覺得我是個肥肥的
the guy everyone thinks is just a flabby...
只愛吃甜甜圈的警察 卻對你有刻板印象
donut-loving cop, stereotyping you. Oh...
不 沒關係 噢 其實你那裏有一個
No, it's okay. Oh, you've actually got...
-有一個 -一個什麼
- There's a... - Um... A what?
在你的脖子上 褶子裏面的
In your neck. The fold.
-哪裏 噢 -那個 嗯 是的
- Where? Oh! - The... Mmm-hmm. Yes.
你跑那裏面去啦 這個小甜甜
There you went, you little dickens! Mmm.
我該去報到了 所以我該往哪走
I should get to roll call, which way do l...?
噢 辦公室在左拐處那邊
Oh, Bullpen's over there to the left.
-真棒 謝謝你 -嗷
- Great. Thank you. - Aw...
那只可憐的小兔子會被生吞活剝的
That poor little bunny's gonna get eaten alive.
嘿 我是霍普斯警官
Hey, Officer Hopps.
你準備好讓世界更美好了嗎
You ready to make the world a better place?
全體注意
Atten-hut!
好了 肅靜 大家都坐下
All right. All right! Everybody sit.
我有三件事情交代
I've got three items on the docket.
首先 大家要注意到
First... we need to acknowledge...
房間裏的大象
the elephant in the room.
弗朗辛
Francine...
生日快樂
Happy birthday.
噢 耶
Oh, yeah.
噢 噢
Oh. Oh.
第二件事
Number two.
有些新同事來了 我應該予以介紹
There are some new recruits with us I should introduce...
但是我不打算介紹
but I'm not going to...
因為我懶得介紹
because I don't care.
最後 我們有十四起哺乳動物失蹤案
Finally, we have 14 missing mammal cases.
都是食肉動物 從巨型北極熊
All predators, from a giant polar bear...
到小水獺
to a teensy little otter.
市政廳催得我緊緊的 要盡快找到他們
And City Hall is right up my tail to find them.
此事是重中之重
This is priority number one.
分配任務
Assignments.
灰熊佐利
Officers Grizzoli...
尖牙狼 德爾加多警官
Fangmeyer, Delgato.
你們組負責
Your teams take missing mammals...
雨林區失蹤案
from the Rainforest District.
麥克角 犀維茨 狼法德警官
Officers McHorn, Rhinowitz, Wolfard.
你們負責撒哈拉廣場那邊
Your teams take Sahara Square.
河馬斯 熊咆洛 象科比警官
Officers Higgins, Snarlov, Trunkaby.
冰原鎮
Tundratown.
最後 我們的第一隻兔子
And finally, our first bunny...
霍普斯警官
Officer Hopps.
交通協管
Parking Duty.
解散
Dismissed.
交通協管
Parking duty?
局長
- Chief! - Hmm.
牛局長
Chief Bogo?
長官 你說有十四起動物失蹤案件
Sir, you said there were 14 missing mammal cases.
-所以呢 -所以我可以處理一起
- So? - So, I can handle one.
你可能忘記了
You probably forgot...
但是在學校裏 我是我們班最優秀的學員
but I was top of my class at the Academy.
沒有忘記 只是不在乎
Didn't forget. Just don't care.
長官 我可不是只會花拳繡腿的兔子
Sir, I'm not just some token bunny.
那這樣的話 一天開一百張罰單
Well, then writing 100 tickets a day...
應該不是難事
should be easy.
一百張罰單 我不會只開一百張罰單的
100 tickets. I'm not gonna write 100 tickets.
我要開二百張罰單
I'm gonna write 200 tickets.
在中午之前
Before noon.
限時兩小時
超時
禁止停車
耶
Boom!
中午之前兩百張罰單
200 tickets before noon!
噢
Oh...
二百零一張
201.
嘿 看著點路 狐貍
Hey, watch where you're going, fox!
嗯
Mmm.
他去哪了
Where'd he go?
聽著 我不知道你大白天在這附近
Listen, I don't know what you're doing skulking...
鬼鬼祟祟的幹什麼
around during daylight hours...
但是我不想給店裏帶來麻煩
but I don't want any trouble in here.
所以趕緊走人
So, hit the road.
我也不想帶來任何麻煩的 先生
I'm not looking for any trouble either, sir.
我只是想買一個大號冰淇淋
I simply want to buy a Jumbo Pop...
給我的孩子
for my little boy.
你想要紅色的 還是藍色的呀
You want the red or the blue, pal?
嗷
Aw...
我真是
I'm such a...
噢 行了 孩子 回去吧
Oh, come on, kid. Back up.
聽著 夥計 為什麼
Listen, buddy. What?
你們鎮上那一片就沒有
There aren't any fox ice cream joints...
狐貍冰淇淋店嗎
in your part of town?
不 不 有
Uh, no, no. There are.
當然有 只是 我的孩子 這個小傻瓜
There are. It's just, my boy, this goofy little stinker...
他喜歡所有和大象有關的東西
he loves all things elephant.
他希望長大成為一隻大象
Wants to be one when he grows up.
這是不是很可愛
Is that adorable?
噢
Oh!
誰忍心破壞他小小的夢想呢 嗯哼 對吧
Who the heck am I to crush his little dreams, huh? Right?
聽著 你可能不識字 狐貍
Look, you probably can't read, fox...
但是這塊牌子上寫著
but the sign says...
「我們有權拒絕向任何動物
"We reserve the right to refuse service...
提供服務」 所以 請出去
"...to anyone." So, beat it.
你擋住後面的人了
You're holding up the line.
你好 抱歉打擾了
Hello? Excuse me.
嘿 開罰單的 你得和
Hey, you're gonna have to wait your turn...
其他人一樣排隊點單
like everyone else, meter maid.
實際上 我是名警官
Actually, I'm an officer.
只是有個小問題
Just had a quick question.
你的顧客們知道
Are your customers aware...
他們的小甜餅和冰淇淋
they're getting snot and mucus...
是鼻涕味的嗎
with their cookies and cream?
你在瞎說什麼
What are you talking about?
我不想給你惹什麼麻煩
Well, I don't want to cause you any trouble...
但是我認為不佩戴鼻套
but I believe scooping ice cream...
直接用鼻子挖冰淇淋
with an ungloved trunk is a Class 3...
是違反衛生條例的
health code violation.
這似乎是個大麻煩
Which is kind of a big deal.
當然 要是你們佩戴好鼻套的話
Of course, I could let you off with a warning...
我也可以只予以警告 還有 或許可以
if you were to glove those trunks and, I don't know...
賣給這位好爸爸和他兒子一個
finish selling this nice dad and his son a...
一個什麼來著
What was it?
一個大號冰淇淋 拜託了
A Jumbo Pop. Please.
一個大號冰淇淋
A Jumbo Pop.
十五美元
$15.
太謝謝你了 謝謝
Thank you so much. Thank you.
噢 不是吧 逗我呢 我沒有帶錢包
Oh, no. Are you kidding me? I don't have my wallet.
我今天真是沒帶腦子出門
I'd lose my head if it weren't attached to my neck.
真是沒辦法
That's the truth.
噢 兒子 對不起 小傢伙
Oh, boy. I'm sorry, pal.
這可能是史上最糟糕的生日了
Got to be about the worst birthday ever.
請不要生我的氣
Please don't be mad at me.
不管怎樣 謝謝你
Thanks anyway.
不用找了
Keep the change.
警官 真是太感謝你了
Officer, I can't thank you enough.
你人真好 真的 我該怎麼報答你呢
So kind, really. Can I pay you back?
噢 不用了 算我請吧
Oh, no, my treat. It just...
只是 看到人們對狐貍抱有
You know, it burns me up to see folks...
既有的偏見 讓我很是憤怒
with such backward attitudes toward foxes.
我只是想說 你是個好爸爸
I just wanna say you're a great dad and just a...
而且口才很棒
a real articulate fella.
噢 你過獎了
Oh, well, that is high praise.
我很少見到能像你這麼平易近人的人
It's rare that I find someone so non-patronizing.
怎麼稱呼警官你呢
Officer...
霍普斯 你叫
Hopps. Mister...
王爾德 尼克·王爾德
Wilde. Nick Wilde.
還有你 小傢伙
And you, little guy...
長大後你想成為大象是嗎
You want to be an elephant when you grow up?
你會成為大象的
You be an elephant.
因為這裏是動物城
Because this is Zootopia.
每個人皆有無限可能
Anyone can be anything.
啊 天吶 我一直都這麼教導他
Oh, boy, I tell him that all the time.
好了 拿著吧 兩爪抓
All right, here you go. Two paws. Yeah.
噢 看這笑容
Oh, look at that smile.
那才是生日快樂的微笑
That's a "Happy birthday" Smile.
好了 跟警官嘟嘟拜拜吧
All right, give her a little bye-bye toot-toot.
嘟嘟
Toot-toot!
拜拜啦
Bye, now.
再見
Goodbye!
噢
Oh!
嘿 小嘟嘟
Hey, little Toot-Toot...
爪子冰棍 天然有機
爪子冰棍
Pawsicles!
旅鼠兄弟銀行
爪子冰棍來一個
Get your pawsicles!
噢
Oh.
木材到了
Lumber delivery.
這顏色是怎麼回事
What's with the color?
顏色
The color?
啊 這是紅木
Uh, that's red wood.
39, 40. There you go.
穿尿布這招太讚了 大傢伙
Way to work that diaper, big guy.
嘿 不跟爸爸來個吻別麼
Hey, no kiss bye-bye for daddy?
明天你再親我
You kiss me tomorrow,
我就咬掉你的臉
I'll bite your face off.
再見
Ciao.
哼 我為你挺身而出 你卻欺騙我
Well. I stood up for you, and you lied to me.
你這個騙子
You liar!
那叫智取 親愛的
It's called a hustle, sweetheart.
還有 我不是騙子 他才是
And I'm not the liar. He is.
嘿
Hey!
好了 狡猾尼克 你被捕了
All right, slick Nick, you're under arrest.
真的嗎 為什麼
Really? For what?
天吶 我不知道 無證銷售食物怎麼樣
Gee, I don't know. How about selling food without a permit.
跨區運輸未申報貨物呢
Transporting undeclared commerce across borough lines.
虛假廣告
False advertising.
許可證 貨物申報回執
Permit. Receipt of declared commerce.
還有我沒有虛假宣傳任何東西 好走不送
And I didn't falsely advertise anything. Take care.
你跟那隻老鼠說那些爪子冰棍桿是紅木
You told that mouse the popsicle sticks were redwood!
沒錯 紅 木 中間有個空格
That's right. "Red wood." With a space in the middle.
紅色的木頭
Wood that is red.
你抓不到我的 胡蘿蔔頭
You can't touch me, Carrots.
我從出生起就幹這行了
I've been doing this since I was born.
不許叫我胡蘿蔔頭
You're gonna want to refrain from calling me Carrots.
我的錯 我只是自然而然地覺得你是來自
My bad. I just naturally assumed...
你是來自某個塞滿胡蘿蔔的小破村 不是嗎
you came from some little carrot-choked Podunk, no?
才不是
Uh, no!
破村是在鹿河鎮
Podunk is in Deerbrooke County...
我是在兔窩鎮長大的
and I grew up in Bunnyburrow.
好吧 你聽聽看這個故事是不是很熟悉
Okay. Tell me if this story sounds familiar.
成績好 理想高 又天真的鄉下小姑娘
Naive little hick with good grades and big ideas...
決定「嘿 聽著 我要搬去動物城
decides, "Hey, look at me! I'm gonna move to Zootopia...
在那裏 食肉動物和食草動物可以和諧共處
where predators and prey live in harmony...
高唱聖歌」
and sing 'Kumbaya."'
結果只發現 該死
Only to find, whoopsie...
我們相處得並不好
we don't all get along.
而那想成為大城市警官的夢想呢
And that dream of becoming a big city cop?
又該死 她不過是個開罰單的
Double whoopsie. She's a meter maid.
再一個該死
And, whoopsie number three-sie...
沒有人在意她或她的夢想
no one cares about her or her dreams.
很快那些夢想都將死去
And soon enough, those dreams die...
然後我們的兔兔意志消沉
and our bunny sinks into emotional...
萎靡不振 住在橋下的紙板箱裏
and literal squalor living in a box under a bridge...
直到最終她別無他法 只好夾著
till finally she has no choice but to go back home...
那毛茸茸又軟綿綿的小尾巴
with that cute, fuzzy-wuzzy little tail between...
滾回家做...
her legs to become...
你來自兔窩鎮 你剛是這麼說的吧
You're from Bunnyburrow, is that what you said?
所以種胡蘿蔔怎麼樣 我說的沒錯吧
So how about a carrot farmer. That sound about right?
噢
Oh!
小心點 不然被粉碎的
Be careful, now, or it won't just...
就不僅僅是你的夢想了
be your dreams getting crushed.
嘿 嘿 沒有人有資格告訴我我能做什麼 不能做什麼
Hey! Hey! No one tells me what I can or can't be!
尤其是某些
Especially not some jerk...
永遠沒有勇氣去嘗試新事物
who never had the guts to try to be...
只願安心做個爪子冰棍小販的混蛋
anything more than a popsicle hustler.
好吧 聽著 每個人來到動物城
All right, look. Everyone comes to Zootopia...
自以為他們擁有無限可能
thinking they can be anything they want.
然而 你並不是
Well, you can't.
你只能是你自己
You can only be what you are.
狡猾的狐貍 蠢笨的兔子
Sly fox, dumb bunny.
我不是蠢兔子
I'm not a dumb bunny.
好吧 那也不是濕水泥
Right. And that's not wet cement.
你永遠都不會成為真正的警察
You'll never be a real cop.
不過 你倒是個挺可愛的交通協管員
You're a cute meter maid, though.
或許哪天你就當上了主管呢
Maybe a supervisor one day.
堅持住噢
Hang in there.
一人份胡蘿蔔
爸爸 & 媽媽
噢 嘿 親爸親媽
Oh, hey, it's my parents.
噢 是她 嗨 小甜心
Oh, there she is! Hi, sweetheart!
嘿 朱迪小傢伙
Hey there, Jude the dude.
第一天執勤感覺怎麼樣啊
How was your first day on the force?
-感覺很好啊 -真的嗎
- It was real great. - Yeah?
一切都如你所願嗎
Everything you ever hoped?
嗯 當然啦
Mmm. Absolutely.
比我想像得更好呢
And more.
大家人都很好 我感覺
Everyone's so nice and I feel like I'm really...
-我真的有所作為 -等會
- making a difference. - Wait a second.
天吶 邦尼 看那件衣服
Holy cripes, Bonnie, look at that.
噢 感謝老天
Oh, my sweet heaven!
朱迪 你是交通協管員嗎
Judy, are you a meter maid?
噢 這個 不 噢 不是 這只是臨時的
Oh, this? No! Oh, no. This is just a temporary thing.
這是警隊裏最安全的工作了
Oh, it's the safest job on the force!
她不是個真警察
Oh, she's not a real cop.
我們的禱告靈驗了
Our prayers have been answered!
真是個好日子
Glorious day!
霍霍 交通協管 交通協管
Oh, meter maid! Meter maid!
-交通協管 交通協管 -爸爸 爸爸
- Meter maid! Meter maid! - Dad. Dad. Dad!
我今天真的很累了 我該...
It's been a really long day. I should really...
說得對 你去休息吧
That's right, you get some rest.
還有很多罰單等著你去開呢
Those meters aren't gonna maid themselves.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
Buh-bye.
嘿 兔子 把那哀怨的音樂關小聲點
Hey, buddy, turn down that depressing music.
別吵人家開罰單的小兔子
Leave the meter maid alone.
你沒聽見她說嗎
Didn't you hear her conversation?
她覺得自己特失敗
She feels like a failure!
-噢 你閉嘴 -噢 你閉嘴
- Oh, shut up! - You shut up!
你閉嘴
You shut up!
你才閉嘴
明天會是新的一天
Tomorrow's another day.
沒錯 但或許會更糟糕
Yeah, but it might be worse!
我只超時了三十秒
I was 30 seconds over!
哼 女士 你是個真英雄呢
Ugh! Yeah, you're a real hero, lady!
我媽咪說她巴不得你死了
My mommy says she wishes you were dead.
臭兔子
Uncool, rabbit.
靠開罰單賺工資是吧
My tax dollars pay your salary.
我是名真警察 我是名真警察
I am a real cop. I am a real cop. I am a real cop.
嘿 嘿 你 兔子
Hey, hey, hey! You, bunny!
先生 你要是有意見的話
Sir. If you have a grievance,
你可以到交通法庭提請異議
you may contest your citation in traffic court.
你在說什麼 我的店吶
What are you talking about? My shop!
-剛被搶了 看 -噢
- It was just robbed! Look! - Oh!
他就要逃走了
He's getting away!
你到底是不是警察
Are you a cop or not?
噢 是 是 不用擔心 先生 包在我身上
Oh, yes! Yes! Don't worry, sir! I've got this!
停下
- Stop! - Huh?
依法束手就擒吧
Stop, in the name of the law!
有本事來抓我呀 死兔子
Catch me if you can, Cottontail!
哇哦 哇哦
Whoa! Whoa!
噢
Whoa.
借過一下
Coming through!
我是麥克角警官 發現一起違法事件
This is Officer McHorn, we got a 10-31.
包在我身上
I got dibs!
霍普斯警官 正在追捕
Officer Hopps. I am in pursuit!
嗚呼
Whoo-whoo!
哇哦
Whoa!
小型齧齒動物
你
You!
站住
Freeze!
嘿 開罰單的 等真警察來了再說
Hey, meter maid! Wait for the real cops!
站住
Stop!
噢
Oh...
Oh!
抱歉 借過
Sorry. Coming through.
抱歉 抱歉 打擾了
Excuse me. Excuse me. Pardon.
一路順風 扁平足
Bon voyage-e, flat foot!
嘿 給我站住
Hey, stop right there!
嘗個甜甜圈吧 死警察
Have a donut, copper!
天吶 你看見那些豹紋印花牛仔緊身褲了嗎
Oh, my God. Did you see those leopard printjeggings?
噢
Oh!
我喜歡你的髮型
I love your hair.
謝謝
Thank you.
來爸爸懷裏
Come to papa.
好吧 請你耐心點
Okay. You're gonna have to be patient...
和其他人一樣好好排隊
and wait in line just like everyone else...
好嗎 奧獺頓女士
Mrs. Otterton. Okay?
我逮到黃鼠狼了
I popped the weasel!
霍普斯
Hopps!
擅離職守
Abandoning your post.
引起恐慌
Inciting a scurry.
魯莽危害齧齒動物
Reckless endangerment of rodents.
但是 公平而言
But, to be fair...
你確實阻止了一起
you did stop a master criminal...
搶劫兩打發霉洋蔥的大案
from stealing two dozen moldy onions.
冒昧更正下 長官
Mmm. Hate to disagree with you, sir...
那些不是洋蔥
but those aren't onions.
那些是拉丁學名為
Those are a crocus varietal...
午夜嚎叫的番紅花品種
called midnicampum holicithias.
它們屬於C類藥用植物 長官
They're a Class-C botanical, sir.
嗯 我家那塊兒的
Well, I grew up in a family...
種植業還是挺發達的
where plant husbandry was kind of a thing.
閉上你的小嘴
Shut your tiny mouth now!
長官 我抓住壞人了
Sir, I got the bad guy.
那是我的職責所在
That's my job.
你的工作是
Your job is putting tickets...
開罰單
on parked cars!
老大
Chief...
奧獺頓太太又來找你了
uh, Mrs. Otterton's here to see you again.
-現在沒空 -好吧 我只想確認下
- Not now. - Okay, I just didn't know...
這次你是否願意接見下
if you'd want to take it this time.
她看起來很沮喪
She seems really upset.
-現在 沒空 -長官
- Not now! - Sir...
我不想做交通協管員
I don't want to be a meter maid...
我想要做名真正的警察
I want to be a real cop.
你覺得市長把你分派給我的時候
Do you think the mayor asked what I wanted...
他問過我想要什麼嗎
when he assigned you to me?
但是 長官
But, sir, if...
生活不是什麼動畫音樂劇
Life isn't some cartoon musical...
不是你唱唱小曲
where you sing a little song...
你那無聊的夢想就會奇跡般成真
and your insipid dreams magically come true.
所以 別固執了
So, let it go.
牛局長 求你了
Chief Bogo, please.
請給我五分鐘
Five minutes of your time. Please.
對不起長官
I'm sorry, sir.
我盡力攔住她了 但她太麻溜了
I tried to stop her. She is super-slippery.
我得去坐下歇會
I gotta go sit down.
夫人 我已經告訴過你了 我們已經竭盡所能
Ma'am, as I've told you, we're doing everything we can.
我的丈夫已經失蹤十天了
My husband has been missing for 10 days.
他叫埃米特·奧獺頓
His name is Emmitt Otterton.
是 我知道
Yes, I know.
他是個花匠
He's a florist.
我們有兩個漂亮的孩子
We have two beautiful children.
他不會就這樣消失的
He would never just disappear.
夫人 我們的探員都非常忙
Ma'am, our detectives are very busy.
求你了
Please.
一定得有人去找我的埃米特
There's got to be somebody to find my Emmitt.
奧獺頓太太
Mrs. Otterton...
我會找到他的
I will find him.
噢
Oh!
謝謝你
Thank you.
-願上帝保佑你 -噢
- Bless you. - Oh!
願上帝保佑你 小兔子
Bless you, little bunny.
噢
Oh.
拿著這個
Take this.
找到我的埃米特 拜託了
Find my Emmitt. Bring him home...
把他帶回我們身邊
to me and my babies, please.
奧獺頓太太 請在門外稍等
Mrs. Otterton, please wait out here.
好的 噢 太謝謝你們了
Of course. Oh, thank you both so much.
就一會
One second.
你被開除了
You're fired.
什麼 為什麼
What? Why?
違抗命令
Insubordination!
現在 我會把這扇門打開
Now. I'm going to open this door...
然後你要告訴那只水獺
and you're going to tell that otter...
你只是個有妄想癥的
you're a former meter maid...
前交通協管員
with delusions of grandeur...
不能接下這個案子
who will not be taking the case!
我剛聽說霍普斯警官要接這個案子
I just heard Officer Hopps is taking the case.
羊市長助理
Assistant Mayor Bellwether.
哺乳動物納招募項目
The Mammal Inclusion Initiative...
真的有所成效
is really starting to pay off.
獅子市長一定會很激動的
Mayor Lionheart is just gonna be so jazzed!
不 不 我們還是先別告訴市長吧
No, no, let's not tell the Mayor just yet.
然後發送 發送成功 就這麼定啦
And I've sent it and it is done, so I did do that.
好了 嗯 這起案件就交由你們妥善處理
All right. Well, I'd say the case is in good hands.
像我們這種小動物真的需要團結在一起 不是嗎
Us little guys really need to stick together, right?
緊密團結
Like glue.
不錯不錯
Good one.
有任何需要就給我打電話
Just call me if you ever need anything, okay?
你在市政廳永遠有我這個朋友 朱迪
You've always got a friend at City Hall, Judy.
好了 拜拜
All right, bye-bye.
謝謝你 女士
Thank you, ma'am.
我給你四十八小時
I will give you 48 hours.
棒
Yes!
就是說兩天內要找到埃米特·奧獺頓
That's two days to find Emmitt Otterton.
好的
Okay.
但是 你要是失敗了 自動請辭
But, you strike out, you resign.
噢 額
Oh! Uh...
好
Okay.
成交
Deal!
很好
Splendid.
豹警官會把完整檔案給你
Clawhauser will give you the complete case file.
給你
Here you go.
失蹤哺乳動物報告
一隻失蹤的水獺
One missing otter.
就這點兒
That's it?
是呀 這是我見過最薄的檔案了
Yikes! That is the smallest case file I've ever seen.
線索 沒有 目擊者 沒有
Leads, none. Witnesses, none.
你還沒法進入電腦系統
And you're not in the computer system yet...
所以 資源 也沒有
so resources, None!
希望你沒有把自己的職業生涯
Oh, I hope you didn't stake your career...
都賭在這起案子上
on cracking this one!
好吧 最後出現地點
Okay. Last known sighting.
能借我用下嗎 謝謝
Can I just borrow... Thank you.
爪子冰棍
Popsicle?
謀殺兇器
The murder weapon.
「爪子冰棍來一個」
Get your popsicle.
沒錯 因為那...那是什麼意思
Yeah. Because that... What does that mean?
意思是
It means...
我有線索了
I have a lead.
嗨 你好啊 又是我
Hi! Hello? It's me, again!
嘿 是嘟嘟警官
Hey, it's Officer Toot-Toot.
噢 不 實際上是霍普斯警官
No. Actually, it's Officer Hopps...
我來是要就一起案件問你些問題
and I'm here to ask you some questions about a case.
什麼事了 交通協管員
What happened, meter maid?
有人把交通錐標偷了嗎
Did someone steal a traffic cone?
那可不是我
It wasn't me.
嘿 胡蘿蔔頭 你會把寶寶吵醒的
Hey, Carrots, you're going to wake the baby.
我得去開工了
I gotta get to work.
先生 這很重要
This is important, sir.
我想你那十美元的爪子冰棍可以靠邊等
I think your $10 worth of popsicles can wait.
小絨兔 我一天可以賺兩百美元好嗎
I make 200 bucks a day, Fluff!
從我十二歲起 每年365天都如此
365 days a year, since I was 12.
時間就是金錢 一邊待著去
And time is money. Hop along.
請你就看看這張照片吧
Please, just look at the picture.
奧獺頓先生在你這買過爪子冰棍 對吧
You sold Mr. Otterton that popsicle, right?
你認識他嗎
Do you know him?
我認識所有人
I know everybody.
我還知道 某個地方
And I also know that, somewhere...
有個玩具店裏的毛絨玩具不見了
there's a toy store missing its stuffed animal...
所以不如你回到你的盒子裏待著去吧
so why don't you get back to your box?
好吧 是你敬酒不吃吃罰酒
Fine. Then we'll have to do this the hard way.
你剛給我的嬰兒車上夾鎖了是嗎
Did you just boot my stroller?
尼克拉斯·王爾德 你被捕了
Nicholas Wilde, you are under arrest.
哈 為什麼 傷害了你的感情嗎
Ha! For what? Hurting your feelings?
逃稅重罪
Felony Tax Evasion.
嗯 從你12歲起 每天兩百美元
Yeah, $200 a day, 365 days a year...
每年365天
since you were 12.
一共20年 所以乘以20
That's two decades, so times 20...
那就是146萬美元
which is $1,460,000, I think.
雖然我不過是只蠢兔子
I mean, I am just a dumb bunny...
也指兔子的繁殖能力
但我們兔子的乘法還是不錯的
but we are good at multiplying.
不管怎樣 根據你的納稅申報表
Anyway, according to your tax forms...
你繳納了 讓我看看 零美元
you reported, let me see here... zero!
不幸的是 謊報稅款
Unfortunately, lying on a federal form...
可是違法行為
is a punishable offense.
五年牢獄
Five years jail time.
你口說無憑 我不承認
Well, it's my word against yours.
小絨兔 我一天可以賺200美元好嗎
200 bucks a day, Fluff!
從我12歲起 每年365天都如此
365 days a year, since I was 12.
實際上 你已經供認不諱了
Actually, it's your word against yours.
如果你想要拿到這支筆的話 你就得幫我
And if you want this pen, you're going to help me...
找到這個可憐的失蹤水獺
find this poor, missing otter...
否則的話 你就得在監獄食堂裏
or the only place you'll be selling popsicles...
賣你的爪子冰棍
is the prison cafeteria.
這叫智取 親愛的
It's called a hustle, sweetheart.
她智取你了 啊哈哈哈
She hustled you.
幹得漂亮
She hustled you good!
尼克 你現在也是個警察了 你會需要個警徽的
You a cop now, Nick. You gonna need one of these.
祝你和這毛絨兔子
Have fun...
合作愉快
working with the fuzz!
老實交代吧
Start talking.
我不知道他現在在哪
I don't know where he is.
只是見過他去哪了
I only saw where he went.
行 我們走吧
Great. Let's go.
那可不是你這隻小可愛兔子
It's not exactly a place for, uh...
該去的地方
a cute little bunny.
別說我可愛好嗎 上車
Don't call me cute. Get in the car.
行行行 你是老大
Okay. You're the boss.
嗨
Hi.
你好
Hello?
額 你好
Um, hello?
你好 你好嗎
Hello? Hello?
嗯
Hmm?
-你好 我叫 -噢
- Hello. My name is... - Oh...
你知道的 我得先
You know, I'm going to hit...
讓你暫停一下
the pause button right there...
我們不需要兔兔童子軍餅乾了
because we're all good on Bunny Scout cookies.
不是那個
Uh... no.
我是霍普斯警官 來自動物城警察局
I'm Officer Hopps, ZPD.
正在尋找一名失蹤的哺乳
I'm looking for a missing mammal...
埃米特·奧獺頓 就是這位
Emmitt Otterton, right here...
他是不是經常來這裏呀
who may have frequented this establishment.
嗯
Hmm.
啊 老埃米特
Yeah, Old Emmitt.
好幾周都沒見他了
Haven't seen him in a couple of weeks.
但是 嘿 你應該問問他的瑜伽教練
But, hey, you should talk to his yoga instructor.
我很樂意帶你們到後面去
I'd be happy to take you back.
噢 十分感謝
Oh, thank you so much. I'd appreciate that...
真的太謝謝你了 真的
more than you can imagine, it would be such...
-啊 你沒穿衣服 -唔
- Ohh! You are naked! - Huh?
噢 當然 這是自然主義俱樂部
Oh, for sure, we're a naturalist club.
沒錯 在動物城 每個人皆有無限可能
Yeah. In Zootopia, anyone can be anything.
這些傢伙 他們可以赤裸生活
These guys, they be naked.
楠吉在極樂池的另一頭
Nangi's just on the other side of the Pleasure Pool.
噢 天吶
Oh, boy.
看到這一幕你可還好
Does this make you uncomfortable?
如果你覺得不舒服 就此放棄也沒什麼丟人的
Because if so, there is no shame in calling it quits.
這有什麼 走吧
Yes, there is.
還真是勇氣可嘉
Boy, that's the spirit.
是 有些哺乳動物說
Yeah, some mammals say...
自然主義生活很奇怪
the naturalist life is weird...
但你知道我怎麼看嗎
but you know what I say is weird?
動物穿衣服才最奇怪呢
Clothes on animals!
看到她啦
- Here we go. - Mmm...
如你所見 楠吉是一頭大象
As you can see, Nangi's an elephant...
所以她記憶力非凡
so she'll totally remember everything.
嗨 楠吉
Hey, Nangi.
這些傢伙想問你點事
These dudes have some questions...
關於埃米特 那只水獺
about Emmitt the otter.
誰
Who?
額 埃米特·奧獺頓
Uh... Emmitt Otterton?
上你的瑜伽課
Been coming to your yoga class for like...
快六年了
6 years?
我不記得有這只河貍
I have no memory of this beaver.
其實 他是一隻水獺
He's an otter, actually.
幾周前的星期三 他還來過 記得嗎
He was here a couple Wednesdays ago, remember?
沒印象
No.
對了 他穿了一件
Yeah, he was wearing...
綠色針織毛衣背心
a green cable-knit sweater vest...
和一條新的闊特維長褲
and a new pair of corduroy slacks.
噢 還戴了一條佩斯利花紋領帶 打了一個可愛的溫莎結
Oh, and a paisley tie, sweet Windsor knot.
還系得很緊 你記得嗎 楠吉
Real tight. Remember that, Nangi?
沒印象
No.
對了 我們倆一起送他出門 然後
Yeah, and we both walked him out, and he got into...
他上了一輛銀邊的大破車
this big old white car with a silver trim.
那車該修修啦 第三個汽缸打不著火了
Needed a tune-up. The third cylinder wasn't firing.
-記得嗎 楠吉 -沒印象
- Remember that, Nangi? - No.
呃 你該不會
Uh... You didn't happen to catch...
還記得車牌號吧
the license plate number, did you?
噢 當然了 車牌號是 2 9
Oh, for sure. It was 2-9...
T H D
T-h-d...
-0 3 -0 3 哇哦
- 0-3. - JUDY: 0-3. Wow.
這個信息很重要 謝謝
This is a lot of great info. Thank you.
給你說了嘛 楠吉記憶力超群
Told you Nangi has a mind like a steel trap.
真希望我也能擁有大象的記憶力
I wish I had a memory like an elephant.
密泉綠洲
嗯 我玩的很愉快
Well, I had a ball.
我幫你找到了線索 不用謝
You are welcome for the clue...
既然查車牌這件事白癡都會
and seeing as how any moron can run a plate...
那我就帶走那支筆 和你拜拜咯
I will take that pen and bid you adieu.
車牌 我查不到車牌啊
The plate. I can't run a plate.
我還沒能進入電腦系統
I'm not in the system yet.
請把筆給我
Give me the pen, please.
你剛才說啥來著
What was it you said?
白癡都會查車牌
"Any moron can run a plate"?
哎呀 要是有個白癡
Gosh. If only there were a moron around...
能幫我查車牌就好了
who were up to the task.
兔子 我照你說的做了
Rabbit, I did what you asked!
你不能永遠吊著我吧
You can't keep me on the hook forever.
不會永遠的 我也只剩下三十六個小時
Not forever. Well, I only have 36 hours left...
來解決這個案子了
to solve this case.
那你到底幫不幫我查車牌
So can you run the plate or not?
其實 我剛想起
Actually, I just remembered...
我在車管所有熟人
I have a pal at the DMV.
閃電是這裏動作最快的傢伙
Flash is the fastest guy in there.
只要有事要辦 找他就對了
If you need something done, he's on it.
希望如此 現在真的爭分奪秒
I hope so. We are really fighting the clock...
刻不容緩啊
and every minute counts.
等等 他們都是樹獺嗎
Wait. They're all sloths?
你剛才明明說會很快的啊
You said this was going to be quick!
怎麼 就算他是樹獺
Are you saying that because he's a sloth...
難道就快不起來了嗎
he can't be fast?
在動物城 任何人皆有無限可能呢
I thought in Zootopia, anyone could be anything.
閃電 閃電 瞬息萬變
Flash, Flash, hundred-yard dash.
老兄 見到你真高興
Buddy, it's nice to see you.
我 見到
Nice to...
你 也很
see you...
高興
too.
嘿 閃電 給你介紹一下我朋友
Hey, Flash, I'd love you to meet my friend.
啊 親愛的 我忘了你叫啥
Uh, darling, I've forgotten your name.
呵呵
Hmm.
朱迪·霍普斯警官 來自動物城警局 你好嗎
Officer Judy Hopps, ZPD, how are you?
我
I am...
現
doing...
在
Just...
很好?
Fine?
過 得
...as well as...
也 還
I can...
-行 -嗯
- be. - Hmm.
- 我 -等著吧
- What... - Hang in there.
有 什麼
...can I...
-能 -我想讓你
- do... - Well, I was hoping...
-幫我查個 -幫你
- you could run a... - ...for you...
我想讓你幫我
Well, I was hoping you could...
的 嗎
...today?
我想讓你幫我們查個車牌號
Well, I was hoping you could run a plate for us.
我們真的很急
We are in a really big hurry.
好的
Sure.
車牌
What's the...
-號碼 -2 9 T
- plate... - 2-9-T...
是多少
...number?
2 9 T H D 0 3
2-9-t-h-d-0-3
Two...
nine...
T H D 0 3
T-h-d-0-3.
H D 0 3
H-d-0-3.
D 0 3
D-0-3.
嗯哼
- Mmm-hmm.
0 3
0-3.
3.
嘿 閃電 想聽個笑話嗎
Hey, Flash, want to hear a joke?
閉嘴
No!
好啊
Sure.
你知道一隻有三個峰的駱駝叫什麼嗎
Okay. What do you call a three-humped camel?
我 不
I don't...
知道
know.
有三個
What...
峰的
do...
駱駝
you call...
-叫 -叫什麼
- a... - Three-humped camel.
什
...three-humped...
麼
camel?
懷孕的駱駝
Pregnant.
哈 哈 確實好搞笑 笑死了
Ha-ha! Yes, very funny, very funny.
請問現在可以專注任務了嗎
Can we please just focus on the...
-嗨 -等一下 等一下
- Hey... - Wait, wait, wait!
普麗西拉
...Priscilla!
噢 不
Oh, no!
怎麼了
Yes...
閃電
Flash?
-你 -噢
- What... - Oh!
知道
Do...
-不 -有 三個
- No! - ...you call a...
峰的駱駝叫什麼 懷孕的駱駝
A three-humped camel? "Pregnant!"
好了 很棒 我們答對了
Okay, great, we got it.
-峰 的 -請你
- ...three... humped... - Please just...
動物城 哺乳動物車輛管理所
車牌號： 29THD03
所有者：冰原鎮轎車服務
地址：動物城冰原鎮常青路755號
-這 -耶 快點
- Here... - Yeah. Hurry.
-給 -謝謝 2 9 T H D 0 3
- ...you... - Thank you. "2-9-T-H-D-0-3."
你
...go.
這輛車登記為冰原鎮轎車服務
It's registered to Tundratown Limo Service.
一輛豪華轎車接走了奧獺頓 這輛車在冰原鎮
A limo took Otterton, and the limo's in Tundratown!
在冰原鎮啊
It's in Tundratown!
動作真快 老兄 愛你 我欠你個人情
Way to hustle, bud. I love you. I owe you.
快走 我們得避過晚高峰
Hurry! We gotta beat the rush hour, and...
已經晚上了嗎
It's night?
鎖住了 真棒
Closed. Great.
唔 我想你
Mmm. And I will bet you...
肯定沒有搜捕令 對吧
you don't have a warrant to get in. Hmm?
真討厭 倒霉死了
Darn it. It's a bummer.
是你故意浪費了一整天的時間
You wasted the day on purpose.
女士 我有一個假警徽
Madam, I have a fake badge.
我不會阻礙你假裝調查的
I would never impede your pretend investigation.
這不是假裝調查 看見了嗎
It's not a pretend investigation. Look, see?
看到他了嗎 這只水獺失蹤了
See him? This otter is missing.
好吧 那他們應該讓一個真警察去找他
Well, then they should've gotten a real cop to find him.
你到底想怎樣
What is your problem?
看到我失敗 讓你對自己悲慘的生活
Does seeing me fail somehow make you feel better...
感到舒心嗎
about your own sad, miserable life?
確實啊 百分之百就是
It does. 100%.
現在 既然你沒有搜捕令
Now, since you're sans warrant...
我想 該到此為止了吧
I guess we're... done?
行 就這樣吧 給你筆
Fine. We are done. Here's your pen.
嘿
Hey!
第一 你扔得軟綿綿得就像隻兔子
First off, you throw like a bunny.
第二 你真是輸不起
Second, you're a very sore loser.
回頭見 毛絨警官
See you later, Officer Fluff.
真可惜一切都結束了 真可惜一切都結束了
So sad this is over. I wish I could've helped more.
其實吧 有合理根據時
The thing is, you don't need a warrant...
並不需要搜捕令
if you have probable cause...
而且 我很確定剛才看到
and I'm pretty sure I saw...
一隻鬼鬼祟祟的動物攀爬柵欄
a shifty lowlife climbing the fence.
所以你得接著幫我了 來吧
So you're helping plenty. Come on.
2 9 T H D 0 3 就是這輛
2-9-T-H-D-0-3. This is it!
北極熊毛
Polar bear fur.
-噢 天哪 -怎麼了
- Oh, my God! - What? What?
田鼠傑瑞的唱片 天鵝絨煙斗
The Velvety Pipes of Jerry Vole.
不過是唱片
But on CD.
這年頭誰還聽唱片啊
Who still uses CDs?
胡蘿蔔頭 如果你要找的水獺來過這裏
Carrots, if your otter was here...
那他一定吃盡了苦頭
he had a very bad day.
都是爪痕
Those are claw marks.
你以前見過這樣的嗎
You ever seen anything like this?
沒見過
No.
噢 等等 看
Oh, wait, look.
就是他 埃米特·奧獺頓
This is him, Emmitt Otterton.
他一定來過這裏
He was definitely here.
你覺得到底發生了什麼
What do you think happened?
噢 不 等一下
Well, now, wait a minute.
北極熊毛 鼠幫樂隊 精美酒杯
Polar bear fur, Rat Pack music, fancy cup?
我知道這是誰的車了 我們得馬上離開
I know whose car this is. We got to go.
什麼 這是誰的車
Why? Whose car is it?
冰原鎮最可怕的罪犯頭頭
The most feared crime-boss in Tundratown.
大家都叫他大先生
They call him Mr. Big.
他討厭我 所以我們得走啊
And he does not like me. So we gotta go!
我不走 這裏是犯罪現場
I'm not leaving. This is a crime scene.
好吧 如果大先生發現我在這裏
Well, it's gonna be an even bigger crime scene...
這犯罪現場就更殘暴了
if Mr. Big finds me here...
所以我們得馬上離開
so we're leaving right now.
雷蒙德
Raymond!
那是凱文嗎 好久不見
And is that Kevin? Long time, no see.
說到好久不見
And, speaking of "No see"...
不如你們忘了我出現過吧 好嗎
how about you forget you saw me, huh?
看在多年的交情上
For old times' sake?
被拒絕了
That's a no.
噢
Oh...
你做了什麼事
What did you do that made...
讓大先生這麼生氣
Mr. Big so mad at you?
我 呃 我賣給他一條價值連城的壁毯
I, uh, I may have sold him a very expensive wool rug...
其實是用一隻臭鼬
that was made from the fur of a skunk...
屁股做的
...'s butt.
噢 我的老天爺
Oh, sweet cheese and crackers.
這是大先生嗎
Is that Mr. Big?
不是
No.
他呢
What about him?
-是他嗎 -不是
- Is that him? - No!
一定是他吧
That's got to be him.
別說話 別說話 別說話
Stop talking, stop talking, stop talking!
-哈 -大先生 尊敬的先生
- Huh. - Mr. Big, sir.
我想有點誤...
This is a simple...
好的
Yeah. Here...
唔
Mmm...
我想這其中有點小小的誤會
This is a simple misunderstanding.
噢
Oh...
今天是我女兒結婚的大喜日子
You come here, unannounced...
你沒說一聲就突然過來
on the day my daughter is to be married.
好吧 其實我們是
Well, actually, we were brought here...
被迫帶到這裏的 所以
against our will, so...
問題的關鍵是 我並不知道那是您的車
The point is, I did not know that it was your car...
我更不知道您女兒今天結婚
and I certainly did not know about your daughter's wedding.
呵
Meh.
我曾經那麼信任你 尼克
I trusted you, Nicky.
我歡迎你來我家
I welcomed you into my home.
我們共享晚餐
We broke bread together.
奶奶還給你做了奶酪卷
Gram-mama made you a cannoli.
然而你怎麼來回報我的慷慨
And how did you repay my generosity?
用一條臭鼬屁股做成的毯子
With a rug made from the butt of a skunk.
一條臭鼬屁股毯
A skunk-butt rug.
你對我毫無敬意
You disrespected me.
對我奶奶毫無敬意
You disrespected my Gram-mama...
我還用你那條毯子裹著她安葬的
who I buried in that skunk butt rug.
我告訴過你 別再出現在我面前
I told you never to show your face here again...
但你又來了
but here you are...
四處打探 和這個
snooping around with this...
你是誰 演員嗎
What are you? A performer?
你穿的什麼衣服
What's with the costume?
先生 我是一名
Sir. I am a...
啞劇演員 她是一個演啞劇的
Mime! She is a mime.
她不能開口說話
This... mime cannot speak.
如果你是啞劇演員就別說話
You can't speak if you're a mime.
不 我是一名警察
- No, I am a cop. - Ugh...
我正在調查埃米特·奧獺頓的案子
And I'm on the Emmitt Otterton case.
證據表明他曾在你車裏
And my evidence puts him in your car.
隨便你怎麼威脅
So intimidate me all you want.
我到死都會查明
I'm going to find out what you did to that otter...
你對那只水獺做了什麼
if it's the last thing I do.
嗯
Meh.
那我只有一個請求
Then I have only one request.
替我和奶奶問個好 凍了他們
Say hello to Gram-mama. Ice 'em.
哇哦
Whoa!
我什麼都沒看見 我什麼都沒說啊
I didn't see nothing! I'm not saying nothing!
以後也沒機會了
And you never will.
-拜託 不要 不要啊 -放我下來
- Please! No, no, no! - Put me down!
如果您還因為毯子的事生氣 我這裏還有很多毯子
If you're mad at me about the rug, I've got more rugs!
噢 爹地 我們該去跳舞了
Oh, Daddy! It's time for our dance!
啊 我們剛才不是說好了嗎
Oh, what did we say?
我結婚這天不許殺人
No icing anyone at my wedding!
被逼無奈啊 寶貝 爹地也沒辦法
I have to, baby. Daddy has to.
扔下去
Ice 'em.
不要 不要 不要啊
No, no, no!
等等
Wait. Please!
她就是昨天救我一命的兔子啊
She's the bunny that saved my life yesterday!
要不然我早被那個大甜甜圈壓死了
From that giant donut.
就是這個兔子嗎
This bunny?
是啊 嗨
Yeah! Hi!
嗨 你的裙子真好看
Hi. I love your dress.
-噢 謝謝誇獎 -噢
- Oh. Thank you. - Oh.
放他們下來
Put 'em down.
你幫了我大忙
You've done me a great service.
我會幫你找到那只水獺的
I will help you find the otter.
你投我以桃 我報之以李
I will take your kindness and pay it forward.
微笑
Smile.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
奧獺頓是我的花匠
Otterton is my florist.
就像我的家人一樣
He's like a part of the family.
他有重要的事想跟我說
He had something important he wanted to discuss.
所以我派車去接他
That's why I sent that car to pick him up.
但他一直沒來
But he never arrived.
因為他被襲擊了
Because he was attacked.
不 是他襲擊了別人
No. He attacked.
奧獺頓嗎
Otterton?
對 就是他 他發瘋了
Otterton. He went crazy.
幾乎要把車都毀了 把我的司機嚇得半死
Ripped up the car, scared my driver half to death...
然後就消失在夜色當中
and disappeared into the night.
可是 他是一隻善良的小水獺啊
But he's a sweet little otter.
親愛的孩子 雖說我們已經進化了 但本質上
Hmm. My child, we may be evolved, but deep down...
仍然是動物
we are still animals.
圖洪加         藤蔓鎮
如果你想找到奧獺頓
You want to find Otterton,
可以問問我的司機
talk to the driver of that car.
他叫曼查斯
His name is Manchas...
住在雨林區
lives in the Rainforest District.
只有他能告訴你更多信息了
Only he can tell you more.
請問 是曼查斯先生嗎
Mr. Manchas?
我是朱迪·霍普斯 來自動物城警局
Judy Hopps, ZPD.
我們想瞭解一下埃米特·奧獺頓發生了什麼事
We just wanna know what happened to Emmitt Otterton.
你
You...
應該先關心一下
should be asking...
-我身上發生了什麼 -哇哦
- what happened to me. - Whoa!
那是小水獺干的嗎
Uh, a teensy otter did that?
到底發生了什麼
What happened?
他是隻野獸
He was an animal.
四爪
Down...
伏地
on all fours.
野蠻殘暴
He was a savage!
一切毫無預兆
There was no warning.
只是他嘴裏一直喊著 午夜嚎叫
He just kept yelling about the Night Howlers.
一遍又一遍地喊 午夜嚎叫
Over and over. The Night Howlers.
你也知道午夜嚎叫是什麼 對嗎
So you know about the Night Howlers, too?
好 很好
Good. Good, good.
因為午夜嚎叫
Because the Night Howlers...
正是我們來找你談的內容
are exactly what we are here to talk about.
-對吧 -是的
- Right? - Yup.
你只需要開門
So, uh, so you just open the door...
告訴我們你知道的一切
and tell us what you know...
我們也會告訴你我們知道的信息 好嗎
and we will tell you what we know. Okay?
好
Okay.
你這狐貍還真聰明
Clever fox.
曼查斯先生
Mr. Manchas?
老兄
Buddy?
你
Are you...
還好嗎
okay?
跑 快跑
Run. Run!
他怎麼了
What is wrong with him?
我不知道啊
I don't know!
跳
Jump!
快過來
Come on!
頭低下
- Head down! - Oh. Oh!
霍普斯警官呼叫
Officer Hopps to Dispatch.
你瞭解夏奇羊嗎 我們時代
Are you familiar with Gazelle, greatest singer
最偉大的歌手 長著犄角的天使
of our lifetime, angel with horns?
好 別走開 接著看噢
Okay, hold on. Keep watching.
你看她後面那個是誰 快看是誰
Who's that beside her? Who is it?
哇 你真是舞技撩人啊 本傑明·豹豪澤
Wow, you are one hot dancer, Benjamin Clawhauser.
那是我 你覺得是真的嗎
It's me! Did you think it was real?
看起來跟真的一樣
It looks so real!
其實是假的 只是一個新手機軟體 等我一下
It's not, it's just a new app. Hold on a second.
豹豪澤
Clawhauser!
豹豪澤 聽我說 這裏有警情
Clawhauser, listen to me, we have a 10-91!
一隻美洲豹發瘋了
Jaguar gone savage!
藤蔓鎮和圖將加交界
Vine and Tuh-junja!
-是圖洪加 -哇哦
- It's "Tuh-hunga!" - Whoa!
好的 我們馬上增援 霍普斯
Okay, we're sending backup! Hopps?
霍普斯
Hopps!
那裏
There!
上那個纜車
Head for the sky trams!
快進來 胡蘿蔔頭
Get in! Carrots.
胡蘿蔔頭
Carrots!
你快走
Go!
不
No, no, no!
老兄
Buddy.
我們同為食肉動物
One predator to another...
不 不 不要
No, no, no...
夥計 你有點緊張了
Now, I can tell you're a little tense...
我現在給你一點私人空間
so I'm just gonna give you a little personal space! Ah!
兔子 不管怎樣 都不要鬆手
Rabbit, whatever you do, do not let go!
-我要鬆手了 -不 你要幹什麼
- I'm gonna let go! - No, you, what?
-一 二 -別這樣
- One, two... - No...
沒聽到嗎 我剛說別 兔子
I said, do not... Rabbit!
胡蘿蔔頭 你救了我一命
Carrots. You saved my life.
嗯 我們警察就是專門幹這個的
Well. That's what we do at the ZPD.
嗯
Hmm.
這下可好
Well, this should be good.
我本以為這只是一起哺乳動物失蹤案
I thought this was just a missing mammal case...
但看來只是冰山一角
but it's way bigger.
奧獺頓先生不只是失蹤了
Mr. Otterton did not just disappear.
我認為他和這只美洲豹 他們野蠻化了 長官
I believe he and this jaguar, they went savage, sir.
野蠻化 這不是石器時代了 霍普斯
Savage? This isn't the Stone Age, Hopps.
動物才不會野蠻化呢
Animals don't "Go savage."
本來也這麼想 直到見到這一幕
I thought so, too, until I saw this.
什麼 他應該就在這的
What? He was right here.
野蠻化的豹子是嗎
The "Savage" Jaguar?
長官 我親眼所見 他差點咬死我們
Sir, I know what I saw. He almost killed us!
或許所有具有攻擊性的食肉動物
Or, maybe any aggressive predator...
在兔子眼裏都很野蠻
looks savage to you rabbits.
我們撤
Let's go!
等等 長官
Wait, sir.
我不是唯一的目擊者
I'm not the only one who saw him.
尼克
Nick!
你覺得我會相信狐貍說的話嗎
You think I'm gonna believe a fox?
但是 他是關鍵的目擊證人 而且我
Well, he was a key witness, and I...
要麼兩天內找到水獺
Two days to find the otter...
要麼你走人
or you quit.
我們說好了的
That was the deal.
警徽
Badge.
-但是長官 我們 -警徽
- But, sir, we... - Badge!
呃 不行
Uh, no.
你說什麼 狐貍
What did you say, fox?
不好意思 我說 不行
Sorry. What I said was, "No."
她不會把警徽交給你的
She will not be giving you that badge.
聽著 你就給她一件搞笑的馬甲
Look, you give her a clown vest...
一輛搞笑的巡邏車
and a three-wheeled joke-mobile...
卻要求她兩天內偵破一個
and two days to solve a case...
你們兩周都破不了的案子
you guys haven't cracked in two weeks?
是啊
Yeah.
怪不得她要找狐貍幫忙
It's no wonder she needed to get help from a fox.
因為你們誰也不會幫她 對嗎
None of you guys were gonna help her, were you?
-我 -這麼說吧 局長
- Ho... - Here's the thing, Chief.
您給了她四十八小時破案
You gave her the 48 hours...
所以嚴格說來我們還有
so, technically, we still have...
十個小時來找到奧獺頓先生
10 left to find our Mr. Otterton...
而我們現在就要去找了
and that is exactly what we're gonna do.
所以恕我們失陪了
So, if you'll excuse us...
我們還有大線索要查 大案子要破
we have a very big lead to follow and a case to crack.
祝好
Good day.
霍普斯警官
Officer Hopps.
謝謝
Thank you.
永遠別被發現別人影響了你
Never let them see that they get to you.
所以
So...
你也有被影響過嗎
things do get to you?
沒有 我意思是 現在不會了
No, I mean, not anymore...
但我曾經
but I was small...
也像你一樣弱小又敏感來著
and emotionally unbalanced like you once.
呵呵
Har-har.
不 我說真的
No, it's true.
那時我才八九歲
I think I was 8, or maybe 9...
我最大的願望
and all I wanted to do...
就是加入小童子軍
was join the Junior Ranger Scouts.
所以我媽媽努力湊錢
So, my mom scraped together enough money...
給我買了一身新制服
to buy me a brand-new uniform...
因為 我發誓 我肯定會適應得很好
because, by God, I was gonna fit in.
就算我是童子軍裏唯一的食肉動物
Even if I was the only predator in the troop.
唯一的狐貍
The only fox.
好了 尼克
Okay, Nick.
我將成為集體中的一員
I was gonna be part of a pack.
準備好了嗎
Ready for initiation?
嗯 我都迫不及待啦
Yeah. Pretty much born ready.
我當時那麼自豪
I was so proud.
好了
Okay.
現在舉起你的右爪 宣讀誓言
Now, raise your right paw and deliver the oath.
我 尼克拉斯·王爾德 保證成為勇敢
I, Nicholas Wilde, promise to be brave...
忠誠 友愛 誠實的人
loyal, helpful, and trustworthy.
就算你是只狐貍
Even though you're a fox?
什麼
What?
不 不要 我做錯什麼了 你們
No. No! What did I do wrong, you guys?
不 拜託 告訴我我做錯什麼了
No, please! Tell me! What did I do wrong?
我做錯什麼了
What did I do?
不
No...
你不會真以為我們會相信一隻
If you thought we would ever trust a fox...
沒戴嘴套的狐貍吧
without a muzzle...
看著挺機靈的沒想到這麼傻
you're even dumber than you look!
愛哭鬼
Cry baby.
噢 他是要哭了嗎
Aw, is he gonna cry?
那天我得到了兩個教訓
I learned two things that day.
第一
One...
我不會再讓任何人看到我的脆弱
I was never gonna let anyone see that they got to me.
那第二呢
And two?
如果全世界都固執認為
If the world's only gonna see a fox...
狐貍是陰險狡猾的
as shifty and untrustworthy...
那也沒必要去嘗試做好人了
there's no point in trying to be anything else.
尼克 你不是那樣的人
Nick, you are so much more than that.
天 看看下面的交通
Boy, look at that traffic down there.
我們接下來連線交通中心的查克
How about we go out to Chuck in Traffic Central.
查克 攝像頭看到的情況如何啊
Chuck, how are things looking on the Jam Cams?
尼克 我很高興你告訴我這些
Nick, I'm glad you told me.
攝像頭
The Jam Cams.
-真的 沒事了 -不 不 不 噓
- Seriously. It's okay. - No, no, no.
交通攝像頭到處都是
There are traffic cameras everywhere!
滿天都是
All over the canopy!
不管那只豹子出了什麼事
Whatever happened to that jaguar...
攝像頭肯定都拍到了
The traffic cams would have caught it!
-沒錯 -哈哈
- Bingo! - Ho-ho!
真狡猾啊 機靈鬼
Pretty sneaky, slick!
但是 如果你之前就沒有權限進入監控系統
However, if you didn't have access to the system before...
我想牛哄哄局長現在也不會讓你進去的
I doubt Chief Buffalo Butt is gonna let you into it now.
不會
No.
但我有個市政廳的朋友或許可以幫忙
But I have a friend at City Hall who might.
呃 市長 要是您能稍微過目這些重要文件
Sir, if we could just review these very important...
市長先生
Sir...
抱歉 先生
I'm so sorry. Sir!
行了 我知道了 羊市長助理 你來處理吧
Okay. I heard you, Bellwether. Just take care of it.
拜託了 然後把我下午的行程推掉 我要出去
Please. And clear my afternoon. I'm going out.
不 不行 但是 您下午要跟
No, no! But, sir, you do have a meeting...
畜牧動物開會啊
with Herds and Grazing.
先生 如果我
Sir, if I could just...
噢 殺了我吧
Oh, mutton chops.
羊市長助理
Assistant Mayor Bellwether?
我們需要你的幫助
We need your help.
市長助理辦公室  請敲門！
我們想要進入交通攝像頭系統
We just need to get into the traffic cam database.
軟綿綿的耶
So fluffy!
喂
Hey!
綿羊從來不讓我靠這麼近的
Sheep never let me get this close.
你不能隨便摸綿羊的毛
You can't just touch a sheep's wool!
像棉花糖一樣誒
It's like cotton candy.
住手
Stop it!
看哪裏的
Where to?
啊 雨林區 藤蔓區和圖洪加交界處
Uh, Rainforest District, Vine and Tujunga.
動物城交通網絡
好了 整座城的交通攝像頭都在這
There! Traffic cams for the whole city.
噢 真挺刺激的
Oh, this is so exciting, actually!
我從沒參與過這麼重要的事
I never get to do anything this important.
但你是動物城的市長助理啊
But you're the Assistant Mayor of Zootopia.
噢 其實就是個名字好聽點的秘書罷了
Oh, I'm more of a glorified secretary.
我覺得獅子市長只是為了爭取綿羊的選票而已
I think Mayor Lionheart just wanted the sheep vote.
但他確實給了個挺好的杯子
But he did give me that nice mug.
世上最棒的爸爸× 市長助理
-噢 -嗯
- Oh. - Hmm.
受賞識的感覺蠻好的
Feels good to be appreciated.
臭綿羊
Smell-wether!
啊 他喜歡叫這個好玩的昵稱
Ugh. That's a fun little name he likes to use.
有一次我叫他臭獅子
I called him Lion-fart once.
他不太樂意 我和你們說
He did not care for that. Let me tell you...
那天我可倒大霉了
it was not a good day for me.
我在 市長
Yes, sir?
我以為你已經幫我推掉下午的行程
I thought you were going to cancel my afternoon!
噢 天吶 我得走了
Oh, dear. I better go.
有什麼發現告訴我一聲
Let me know what you find.
我真高興能
It was really nice for me to be...
-趁花還沒謝 -噢
- While we're young... - Oh...
臭綿羊
Smell-wether!
你猜她睡不著的時候 會不會數自己
You think when she goes to sleep she counts herself?
閉嘴 好了 交通攝像頭
Oh, shush. Okay, traffic cams.
圖洪加 圖洪加 找到了
Tujunga, Tujunga... We're in.
-這些都是誰啊 -額
- Who are these guys? - Ugh.
森林狼 看看這些傻冒
Timberwolves. Look at these dumb-dumbs.
我敢打賭肯定有一隻要開始嚎叫了
Bet you a nickel one of them is gonna howl.
看吧 我說
And there it is.
狼幹嘛非叫不可呢 這簡直
What is it with wolves and the howling? It's like...
嚎叫 午夜嚎叫
Howlers. Night Howlers.
曼查斯怕的就是這個 是狼
That's what Manchas was afraid of! Wolves!
午夜嚎叫說的就是狼
The wolves are the Night Howlers.
如果是他們抓走了曼查斯
If they took Manchas...
他們肯定也抓走了奧獺頓
I'll bet they took Otterton, too.
我們要做的就是找出他們去了哪
All we gotta do is find out where they went.
等等 他們哪去了
Wait, where did they go?
知道嗎 要是我幹了什麼違法亂紀的事
You know, if I wanted to avoid surveillance...
不想被監控逮到的話
because I was doing something illegal...
當然我可沒真幹過
which I never have...
我會走維修中的6B隧道
I would use the maintenance tunnel 6B.
所以他們就會從
Which would put them out...
這裏出來
right there.
好啊 看看你 小神探
Well, look at you, Junior Detective.
知道嗎 我覺得你
You know, I think you'd actually...
是塊當警察的料
make a pretty good cop.
呃 別鬧了
Ugh. How dare you.
阿卡夏小路
Acacia Alley?
費卡思地下通道
Ficus Underpass.
-南部峽谷 -嗯哼
- South Canyon. - Mmm-hmm.
他們要出城了
They're heading out of town.
那條路是去哪的
Where does that road go?
崖邊收容所
蓋瑞 停下
Gary, quit it!
你會引起狼嚎的
You're gonna start a howl.
不是我起的頭
I didn't start it!
快走
Come on.
你這只聰明的兔子
You are a clever bunny.
這裏好像曾經是醫院啊
It looks like this was a hospital.
嗯 你先請 你是警察
You know, after you. You're the cop.
-好了 沒問題 -額
- Okay, all clear. - Ugh.
設備都很新
All this equipment is brand new.
胡蘿蔔頭
Carrots.
爪痕
Claw marks.
是啊 超級大爪痕 我說 什麼動物
Yeah, huge, huge claw marks. I mean, what kind of...
曼查斯先生
Mr. Manchas.
是他
It's him.
找到水獺了
We found our otter.
奧獺頓先生
Mr. Otterton.
我是朱迪·霍普斯警官 您太太讓我來找您
My name is Officer Judy Hopps. Your wife sent me to find you.
我們現在救你出去
We're gonna get you out of here now.
還是算了
Or not.
我覺得他不太想回家找他太太
Guess he's in no rush to get home to the missus.
十一 十二 十三 十四
11,12,13,14...
不算曼查斯的話 總共有十四個
Not including Manchas, it's 14.
牛局長說有十四起哺乳動物失蹤案
Chief Bogo handed out 14 missing mammal files.
他們都在這裏
They're all here.
所有失蹤的哺乳動物都在這裏
All the missing mammals are right here.
夠了 別找借口了 醫生
Enough! I don't want excuses, Doctor!
我要的是答案
I want answers.
獅子市長 拜託
Mayor Lionheart, please.
我們已經盡力了
We're doing everything we can.
真的嗎
Really?
我這有十幾隻動物
Because I got a dozen and a half animals here...
瘋得連爹娘都認不出了
who have gone off-the-rails crazy...
而你找不出原因
and you can't tell me why.
我可一點都不覺得你們盡力了
Now, I'd call that awfully far from "Doing everything."
市長
Sir...
可能需要考慮他們的天性了
it may be time to consider their biology.
什麼 天性是什麼意思
What? What do you mean "Biology?"
只有食肉動物野蠻化了
The only animals going savage are predators.
我們不能隱藏真相 我們得公開這件事
We cannot keep it a secret. We need to come forward.
嗯 好主意 公開透明
Hmm. Great idea. Tell the public.
但是你覺得他們
And how do you think they're...
會怎麼看待市長我呢
gonna feel about their mayor...
我可是頭獅子
who is a lion?
那我就完蛋了
I'll be ruined!
好吧 那牛局長怎麼看
Well, what does Chief Bogo say?
牛局長還不知情
Chief Bogo doesn't know.
而我們不能讓他知道
And we are going to keep it that way.
噢 不 不要 糟了
Oh, no, no, no!
這裏有人
Someone's here.
市長 您得離開這裏 快走
Sir, you need to go, now!
保安 封鎖這片區域
Security! Sweep the area!
太好了 我們死定了 死定了
Great! We're dead. We're dead.
就這樣了 我死定了 你死定了 大家都死定了
That's it. I'm dead, you're dead. Everybody's dead!
你會游泳嗎
Can you swim?
啥 我會游泳嗎 是的 我會 怎麼了
What? Can I swim? Yes, I can swim. Why?
不 不
No, no, no!
胡蘿蔔頭 霍普斯 朱迪
Carrots! Hopps! Judy!
我們得去告訴牛局長
We gotta tell Bogo!
哇噢
Wow!
你真是舞技撩人啊 牛局長
You are one hot dancer, Chief Bogo.
-牛局長 -沒空
- Chief Bogo! - Not now!
-等等 那是夏奇羊嗎 -不是
- Wait, is that Gazelle? - No.
我是夏奇羊 你真是舞技撩人
I'm Gazelle, and you are one hot dancer.
你也下了這個應用 嗷
You have the app too? Oh...
局長
Chief!
豹豪澤 你沒看到我在研究
Clawhauser, can't you see I'm working...
哺乳動物失蹤案嗎
on the missing mammal cases?
噢 是啊 當然 對了 長官
Oh, oh, oh! Yes of course! About that, sir.
剛剛霍普斯警官打電話來說
Officer Hopps just called.
她找到所有失蹤動物了
She found all of them.
哇噢 真是厲害
Wow! I'm impressed.
獅子市長 你有權
Mayor Lionheart, you have the right...
保持沉默 你所說...
to remain silent. Anything...
你根本不懂 我是在保護這座城市
You don't understand. I was trying to protect the city!
你只是想保住烏紗帽而已
You were just trying to protect your job.
不 聽著 我們還不知道這背後的原因
No. Listen, we still don't know why this is happening.
這會毀了動物城的
It could destroy Zootopia.
你有權保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
但你所說的話
Anything you say can and will...
都會被當做呈堂證供
be used against you in a court of law.
你有權...
You have the right...
女士們先生們
Ladies and gentlemammals.
十四隻哺乳動物失蹤了
14 mammals went missing...
但全都被我們新上任的警官找到了
and all 14 have been found by our newest recruit...
她過會兒就會與你們進行交流
who will speak to you in a moment.
但首先 讓我提醒你們...
But first, let me remind you...
啊 我好緊張
Ugh. I'm so nervous.
好了 新聞發佈會小貼士
Okay. Press Conference 101.
你想表現好的話
You wanna look smart?
就用你自己的問題回答他們的問題
Answer their question with your own question...
然後回答你自己的問題 打個比方
and then answer that question. Like this.
「請問 霍普斯警官
"Excuse me. Officer Hopps...
能跟我們說說案子的事情嗎」
"Uh, what can you tell us about the case?"
「嗯 這案子很棘手嗎
"Well, was this a tough case?
是的 的確很棘手」看懂了嗎
"Yes. Yes, it was." You see?
你應該跟我一起上台去
You should be there with me.
我們一起破的案
We did this together.
我是警察嗎 不 我不是
Well, am I a cop? No. No, I am not.
可別這麼說
Hmm. Funny you should say that...
因為 我一直在想
because I've been thinking...
有個搭檔也挺好的
It would be nice to have a partner.
給你 可以拿來寫點什麼
Here. In case you need something to write with.
在220個小時內
At twenty-two hundred hours...
我們找到所有失蹤動物
we found all these missing animals...
霍普斯警官 該你上台了
Officer Hopps, it's time.
他們看起來身體狀況良好
They appear to be in good health, physically...
但精神不佳
...if not emotionally.
接下來 話筒交給
So now, I'll turn things over...
破案的警官
to the officer who cracked the case.
朱迪·霍普斯警官
Officer Judy Hopps.
-霍普斯警官 -霍普斯警官
- Officer Hopps! - Officer Hopps!
這邊
Over here!
請問吧
Yes?
能不能告訴我們那些野蠻化的動物是怎麼回事
What can you tell us about the animals that went savage?
嗯 你所問及的動物
Well, the animals in question, um...
他們都是不同種族的嗎
Are they all different species?
是的 是的 的確如此
Yes. Yes, they are.
好吧 那其中有什麼聯繫嗎
Okay, so what is the connection?
噢 我們只知道
Oh, all we know is that they...
他們都是食肉動物
are all members of the predator family.
所以 只有食肉動物會野蠻化嗎
So, predators are the only ones going savage?
說得沒... 是 說得沒錯 沒錯
That is ac... Yes, that is accurate. Yes.
為什麼 為什麼會這樣
Why? Why is this happening?
我們還不知道
We still don't know.
這可能與動物天性有關
It may have something to do with biology.
這是什麼意思
What do you mean by that?
生物因素
A biological component.
你懂的 他們的DNA決定的
You know, something in their DNA.
DNA 能詳細說說嗎
In their DNA? Can you elaborate on that, please?
好的 我的意思是幾千年前
Yes, what I mean is, thousands of years ago...
食肉動物依賴於他們的捕食天性
uh, predators survived through their aggressive...
而生存
hunting instincts.
由於某種原因
For whatever reason...
他們似乎回到了
they seem to be reverting back...
原始的 野蠻的樣子
to their primitive, savage ways.
就是如此
Of course they did.
啊 他是要哭了嗎
Aw, is he gonna cry?
霍普斯警官 這類事件還會再次發生嗎
Officer Hopps, could it happen again?
有可能 所以我們要保持警惕
It is possible. So we must be vigilant.
而動物城警局會嚴陣以待 隨時準備保護你們
And we at the ZPD are prepared and are here to protect you.
會有更多的動物野蠻化嗎
Will more mammals go savage?
你們採取了哪些保護措施啊
What is being done to protect us?
你們考慮要把
Have you considered
食肉動物強制隔離嗎
a mandatory quarantine on predators?
好了 謝謝你 霍普斯警官
Okay, thank you, Officer Hopps.
時間到了
Uh, that's all the time that we have.
問答環節結束
No more questions.
我表現得好嗎
Was I okay?
噢 挺好的
Oh, you did fine.
好快啊
Oh, that went so fast.
我都沒機會提到你
I didn't get a chance to mention you...
或者談談我們是怎麼
or say anything about how we...
噢 我覺得你說的夠多了
Oh, I think you said plenty.
什麼意思
What do you mean?
「顯然跟生物因素有關」
Clearly there's a biological component?
「這些食肉動物可能回到了
"These predators may be reverting back..."
原始的 野蠻的樣子」
To their primitive, savage ways?"
你認真的嗎
Are you serious?
我只是實話實說啊
I just stated the facts of the case.
我是說 兔子可不會野蠻化
I mean, it's not like a bunny could go savage.
是啊 但是狐貍會的 是吧
Right. But a fox could, huh?
尼克 別鬧了 你跟他們不一樣
Nick, stop it. You're not like them.
現在你還區分出陣營了是吧
Oh, there's a "Them" Now?
你懂我的意思吧
Ugh. You know what I mean.
你不是那種食肉動物啊
You're not that kind of predator.
需要戴嘴套的那種嗎
The kind that needs to be muzzled?
讓你需要隨身攜帶
The kind that makes you think...
防狐噴霧的那種嗎
you need to carry around fox repellent?
對 我第一次見你的時候
Yeah, don't think I didn't...
就注意到這個小東西了
notice that little item the first time we met.
好 那我問你 你怕我嗎
So let me ask you a question. Are you afraid of me?
你覺得我會發瘋嗎
Do you think I might go nuts?
你覺得我會野蠻化嗎
Do you think I might go savage?
你覺得我會想要
Do you think I might try to...
吃掉你嗎
eat you?
我就知道
I knew it.
我還以為真的有人會相信我呢 結果 呵
Just when I thought somebody actually believed in me, huh.
你最好還是別找食肉動物做搭檔了
Probably best if you don't have a predator as a partner.
不 尼克 尼克
No. Nick. Nick!
霍普斯警官 你剛剛是被那只食肉動物威脅了嗎
Officer Hopps! Were you just threatened by that predator?
沒有 他是我朋友
No, he's my friend.
我們連朋友都不能相信了嗎
We can't even trust our own friends?
我沒有這麼說 讓一下
That is not what I said! Please!
我們安全嗎
Are we safe?
狐貍也野蠻化嗎
Have any of our foxes gone savage?
壞消息接連席捲這個被恐懼包圍的城市
More bad news in this city gripped by fear.
冰原鎮悲劇
這頭馴鹿狀況危險
A caribou is in critical condition...
它被發瘋的
the victim of a mauling...
北極熊打傷
by a savage polar bear.
繼霍普斯警官聲稱此類暴力事件
This, the 27th such attack, comes just one week...
與食肉動物有關後
after ZPD Officer Judy Hopps connected the violence...
這一周已經發生二十七起類似案件
to traditionally predatory animals.
與此同時 由流行巨星夏奇羊
Meanwhile, a peace rally organized...
和平集會爆發緊張衝突
組織的和平集會
by pop star Gazelle...
遭到強烈抵制
was marred by protest.
滾回森林裏 野獸
Go back to the forest, predator!
我是大草原來的
I'm from the savanna!
動物城是一個特別的地方
Zootopia is a unique place.
夏奇羊表明立場
是一個瘋狂 美麗又多元的城市
It's a crazy, beautiful, diverse city...
我們因差異而精彩
where we celebrate our differences.
這不是我認識的動物城
This is not the Zootopia I know.
我認識的動物城比這好得多
The Zootopia I know is better than this.
我們不會盲目地互相指責
We don't just blindly assign blame.
我們也不知道為什麼這類襲擊持續發生
We don't know why these attacks keep happening...
但將所有食肉動物
but it is irresponsible...
打上野獸的標籤是不負責任的行為
to label all predators as savages.
這不是我的埃米特
That's not my Emmitt.
我們不能讓恐懼分裂我們
We cannot let fear divide us.
請把我愛的動物城還回來
Please give me back the Zootopia I love.
走吧 霍普斯警官
Come on, Hopps.
新市長要見我們
The new mayor wants to see us.
市長 為什麼
The mayor? Why?
你現在可是個大人物了
It would seem you've arrived.
豹豪澤警官
Clawhauser?
你在做什麼
What are you doing?
他們認為 人們走進
They thought it would be better...
動物城警局時 第一眼看到的
if a predator such as myself...
不是我這樣的食肉動物
wasn't the first face that you see...
比較好吧
when you walk into the ZPD.
什麼
What?
他們準備把我調去檔案室
They're gonna move me to records.
就在樓下
It's downstairs.
就在鍋爐房的旁邊
It's by the boiler.
霍普斯
Hopps!
正直 誠實 勇敢
呃 我不懂
Um, I don't understand.
我們城市裏百分之九十是食草動物 朱迪
Our city is 90% prey, Judy...
而他們現在都很害怕
and right now they're just really scared.
對他們來說你就是英雄 他們信任你
You're a hero to them. They trust you.
所以我和牛局長希望
And so that's why Chief Bogo and I...
你可以成為動物城警局的形象代言
want you to be the public face of the ZPD.
我 不是
I'm... not...
不是一個英雄
I'm not a hero.
我來是想讓世界變得更美好 但是
I came here to make the world a better place...
我似乎搞砸了
but I think I broke it.
你沒這麼大本事 霍普斯
Don't give yourself so much credit, Hopps.
這世界本來就不美好
The world has always been broken...
所以才需要像你這樣的
that's why we need good cops.
好警察
Like you.
恕我直言 長官 一個好警察
With all due respect, sir, a good cop...
應該盡責服務 保護市民
is supposed to serve and protect.
幫扶城市
Help the city.
而不是分裂人心
Not tear it apart.
我不配戴這枚警徽
I don't deserve this badge.
霍普斯
Hopps...
朱迪 你今天的成績是你辛苦換來的
Judy, you've worked so hard to get here.
這是你從小的願望
It's what you wanted since you were a kid.
你不能放棄啊
You can't quit.
謝謝你們給我的機會
Thank you for the opportunity.
騷亂愈演愈烈 城市走向分裂
一打胡蘿蔔
A dozen carrots.
-謝謝 -祝您生活愉快
- Thanks. - Have a nice day.
走吧
Come on.
嗨 朱迪 朱迪小傢伙
Hey, there, Jude. Jude the dude.
還記得這個小名兒嗎 怎麼了呀
Remember that one? How we doing?
很好
I'm fine.
你不好 你的耳朵耷拉著呢
You are not fine. Your ears are droopy.
我怎麼這麼自信自己能有所作為
Why did I think I could make a difference?
因為你一直敢於嘗試 這就是原因
Because you're a trier, that's why.
你一直如此
You've always been a trier.
噢 我試過了
Oh, I tried.
結果讓那麼多無辜的食肉動物
And it made life so much worse...
生活雪上加霜
for so many innocent predators.
噢 不是所有噢
Oh, not all of them, though.
真是說曹操
Speak of the devil.
曹操到
Right on time.
吉迪恩·格雷 糕點坊
那是吉迪恩·格雷嗎
Is that Gideon Grey?
是的 沒錯 我們現在一起合作了
Yep. It sure is. We work with him now.
他是我們的搭檔
He's our partner.
還是多虧了你
And we never would have considered it...
讓我們敞開心胸
had you not opened our minds.
沒錯
That's right.
我是說 這小子現在已經是
I mean, Gid's turned into one of...
三窩區最頂尖的糕點師之一了
the top pastry chefs in the tri-burrows.
這
That's...
你們這麼做真的很酷啊
That's really cool, you guys.
吉迪恩·格雷
Gideon Grey.
萬萬想不到啊
I'll be darned.
嗨 朱迪 我想為我小時候的
Hey, Judy. I'd just like to say I'm sorry...
行為道歉
for the way I behaved in my youth.
我那時不夠自信 所以總是一副
I had a lot of self-doubt, and it manifested itself...
兇神惡煞 恃強凌弱的樣子
in the form of unchecked rage and aggression.
我當時是個大混球
I was a major jerk.
嗯 我現在也知道當混球的滋味了
Oh, I know a thing or two about being a jerk.
不管怎麼說 我給你們帶了一些派
Anyhow, I brought y'all these pies.
嘿 孩子們 小心別踩到
Hey, kids, don't you run through...
那些午夜嚎叫[拉丁學名]
that midnicampum holicithias.
哇 哇 哇
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
現在這可是四美元一朵的天價花啊 老霍
Well, now, there's a $4 word, Mr. H.
我們家一直管它們叫午夜嚎叫
My family always just called them Night Howlers.
等等 你說什麼
I'm so... What did you say?
噢 他在說花的事兒呢 朱迪
Oh, Gid's talking about those flowers, Judy.
我種來幫農作物驅蟲
I use them to keep the bugs off the produce...
但鑒於你叔叔特裏的遭遇
but I don't like the little ones going near 'em...
我不希望孩子們離那些花過近
on account of what happened to your uncle Terry.
是啊 特裏在我們小時候吃過一整株
Yeah, Terry ate one whole when we were kids...
然後整個人都瘋了
and went completely nuts.
他狠狠咬了你媽媽一口
He bit the dickens out of your mother.
兔子也可以變野蠻
A bunny can go savage.
野蠻 這個詞有點嚴重了
Savage? Well, that's a strong word.
但是真的咬的我疼死了
But it did hurt like the devil.
對啊 當然疼了
Well, sure it did!
那一口咬的那麼大
There's a sizable divot in your arm.
必須是野蠻啊
I'd call that savage.
午夜嚎叫不是狼 是花
Night Howlers aren't wolves, they're flowers!
是花讓食肉動物野蠻化的
The flowers are making the predators go savage!
就是這個
That's it!
這就是我一直尋找的突破口
That's what I've been missing!
噢 鑰匙
Oh, keys!
鑰匙 快點 快點
Keys. Keys, keys! Hurry! Come on!
噢 謝謝 愛你們 拜
Oh! Thank you! I love you! Bye!
你知道她在說什麼嗎 邦尼
You catch any of that, Bon?
完全不懂
Not one bit.
這樣我就放心了
Oh, that makes me feel a little bit better.
我以為就我一個人聽不懂呢
I thought she was talking in tongues or something.
誰啊
Who is it?
我得找到尼克
I need to find Nick.
拜託
Please.
尼克
Nick?
Nick!
噢 尼克
Oh, Nick.
午夜嚎叫不是狼
Night Howlers aren't wolves.
是有毒的花
They're toxic flowers.
我想是有人故意針對食肉動物
I think someone is targeting predators on purpose...
逼他們野蠻化
and making them go savage!
哇
Wow.
真有趣呢
Isn't that interesting?
等等 拜託
Wait... Wait! Listen...
我知道你不會原諒我的
I know you'll never forgive me!
但我不怪你
And I don't blame you.
我也不會原諒自己 我那麼無知
I wouldn't forgive me either. I was ignorant...
不負責 心胸狹隘
And irresponsible and small-minded.
但食肉動物不應該因為我的錯誤而受苦
But predators shouldn't suffer because of my mistakes.
我得補救這一切
I have to fix this.
但沒有你我做不到
But I can't do it without you.
等我們結束這一切
And after we're done...
你再恨我
you can hate me.
也不遲啊
And... And that'll be fine.
因為我是一個過分的朋友
Because I was a horrible friend...
我傷害了你
and I hurt you...
你一直都是對的 所以你大可以離開我
and you can walk away knowing that you were right all along.
我真的是只蠢兔子
I really am just a dumb bunny.
別擔心 胡蘿蔔頭 四十八小時之後
Don't worry, Carrots. I'll let you erase it...
我就刪了它
in 48 hours.
好啦 來抱抱
All right. Get in here.
好啦好啦 小兔子 怎麼說哭就哭了
Okay. Oh, you bunnies. You're so emotional.
好啦 深呼吸
There we go. Deep breath.
你是不是想偷這只錄音筆呀
Are you just trying to steal the pen?
是不是呀
Is that what this is?
你踩到我的尾巴了 抬腳 抬腳
You are standing on my tail, though. Off, off, off, off...
不好意思
Oh, I'm sorry.
噢 我以為你們只種胡蘿蔔呢
Ooh, I thought you guys only grew carrots.
好吃 你有什麼計劃
Mmm. What's the plan?
我們要追蹤午夜嚎叫
We are gonna follow the Night Howlers.
好啊 怎麼追
Okay. How?
知道這貨嗎
Know this guy?
當然 我告訴你 每個人我都認識
Uh-huh. I told you. I know everybody.
公爵正版電影
哈哈 瞧一瞧 看一看 要啥有啥
Well, hello. Step right up. Anything you need, I got it.
超能豬戰隊 魔馬奇緣 犀牛破壞王
全是你喜歡的電影
All your favorite movies!
我還有沒放映的電影喲
I got movies that haven't even been released yet.
喵阿娜 長頸國歷險記 浮冰奇緣2
嘿 八五折如何 八折 你說個價 來嘛
Hey, 15% off! 20! Make me an offer! Come on!
哇 看看這是誰呀 盜版公爵
Well, well, look who it is. The duke of bootleg.
你來幹嘛 王爾德
What's it to you, Wilde?
你不該去賣冰棍什麼的嗎
Shouldn't you be melting down a popsicle or something?
喲 這不是兔兔警官嘛
Hey, if it isn't Flopsy the Copsy.
我們都知道你偷的
We both know those weren't moldy onions...
可不是洋蔥
I caught you stealing.
你要這些午夜嚎叫
What were you gonna do with...
幹嘛呢 黃肅狼
those Night Howlers, Wezzleton?
是黃鼠狼 黃鼠狼公爵
It's Weaselton! Duke Weaselton!
我才不告訴你 兔子
And I ain't talking, rabbit.
你也沒法逼我開口
And there ain't nothing you can do to make me.
凍了他
Ice him.
你這卑鄙老鼠
You dirty rat!
幹嘛幫她啊 她可是警察啊
Why are you helping her? She's a cop!
她還是我未來孫女的教母呢
And the godmother to my future granddaughter.
我要給她起名為朱迪
I'm gonna name her Judy.
凍了這只黃鼠狼
Ice this weasel.
好吧 好吧 別這樣 我招 我招
All right, all right, please! I'll talk! I'll talk.
我偷午夜嚎叫 是要拿去賣
I stole them Night Howlers so I could sell 'em.
他們的出價我不能不動心啊
They offered me what I couldn't refuse.
錢
Money.
你賣給誰了
And to whom did you sell them?
公羊道格
A ram named Doug.
我們在地下有個接頭地點
We got a drop spot underground.
小心點
Just watch it.
道格可不友好
Doug is the opposite of friendly.
十分兇狠
He's unfriendly.
走吧
Come On.
黃鼠狼沒撒謊
The weasel wasn't lying.
嗯 看來道格壟斷了
Yeah, looks like old Doug's cornered...
午夜嚎叫的市場
the market on Night Howlers.
我是道格
You got Doug here.
目標是誰
What's the mark?
撒哈拉廣場的獵豹 明白
Cheetah in Sahara Square. Got it.
你認真的嗎 我知道他們很快
You serious? Yeah, I know they're fast.
我能打得中
I can hit him.
聽著 我能從窗口射中一隻
Listen, I hit a tiny little otter...
坐在車裏的小水獺
through the open window of a moving car.
好 完事給你打電話
Yeah, I'll buzz you when it's done.
或者你可以看新聞
Or you'll see it on the news.
看哪個先來吧
You know, whichever comes first.
嘿 道格 開門 你的拿鐵來了
Hey, Doug, open up! We've got your latte.
好了 沃特和傑西回來了 我要走了
All right. Woolter and Jesse are back, so I'm leaving now.
掛了
Out.
嘿 你要去哪 你要去哪兒 回來
Hey. Where are you going? Get back here!
你在幹嘛 他會看到你的
What are you doing? He's gonna see you!
你在看什麼 嘿
What are you looking at? Hey!
不管你在想什麼 都別想了
Whatever you're thinking, stop thinking it. Carrots!
胡蘿蔔頭
Carrots!
這次最好多加點奶泡
It better have the extra foam this time.
嘿 開門
Hey, open up!
你在幹嘛 你把我們困在這裏了
What are you doing? You just trapped us in here.
我們得把這些證據送到警局
We need to get this evidence to the ZPD!
好 這不是嗎 拿到了
Okay. Great! Here it is. Got it!
-不 是所有的 -等等 什麼
- No. All of it! - Wait, what?
噢 棒極了 你現在又成列車長了是吧
Oh, great, you're a conductor now, huh?
嘿 聽著 想讓這老破車開動
Hey, listen. It would take a miracle...
只能靠奇跡了
to get this rust-bucket going.
哇噢 老天顯靈了
Well. Hallelujah.
實驗室出了點狀況
We kinda got a situation at the lab.
現在更糟了
Oh, it just got worse!
任務完成
Mission accomplished.
我現在拉一下勝利的
Would it be premature for me...
嘟嘟號角 會很幼稚嗎
to do a little victory toot-toot?
好吧 就一下
All right. One toot-toot.
好了 這個心願已達成
Well, I can cross that off the bucket list.
我可能得撤銷剛剛那個勝利嘟嘟了
I may have to rescind that victory toot-toot.
也許只是冰雹呢
Maybe that's just hail.
給我過來
Come here!
退後
Back off! Oh!
他來啦
Incoming!
胡蘿蔔頭
Carrots!
別停 繼續開
Don't stop! Keep going!
不 不 拜託你別停
No, no! Please stop!
別讓車停下
Do not stop this car!
加速 尼克 加速
Speed up, Nick! Speed up!
對面有車來了
There's another train coming!
相信我 加速
Trust me. Speed up!
快停車
Stop the train!
嘿
Hey!
需要幫忙嗎
Need some help?
噢 不 不不不 太快了
Oh, no, no, no! Too fast! Too fast!
停下
Hold on!
我想我們該下車了
I think this is our stop!
好吧 也許 有些證據還在呢
Okay, maybe some of the evidence survived.
一切都沒了
Everything is gone.
我們什麼都沒了
We've lost it all.
除了這個
Oh, except for this.
-噢 尼克 太棒了 -嗷
- Ow. - Ooh, Nick! Yes!
來吧 我們得趕緊去警局
Come on! We gotta get to the ZPD.
從國家歷史博物館穿過去
Cut through the Natural History Museum!
到啦
There it is!
朱迪
Judy!
羊市長
Mayor Bellwether!
我們查明原因了
We found out what's happening.
有人用毒鏢射擊食肉動物
Someone's darting predators with a serum.
這就是他們野蠻化的原因
That's what's making them go savage.
我真為你感到驕傲 朱迪 你做的太棒了
I'm so proud of you, Judy. You did just a super job!
謝謝您 女士
Thank you, ma'am.
你怎麼知道在哪裏找到我們
How did you know where to find us?
現在起我來接手這案子吧
I'll go ahead and I'll take that case now.
我看
Uh, you know what?
不如還是尼克和我直接送到警局吧
I think Nick and I will just take this to the ZPD.
跑
Run.
抓住他們
Get them.
啊
Ahh!
胡蘿蔔頭
Carrots!
我扶著你
I got you!
沒事的 我們走
Come here, come here.
好了 現在 放輕鬆
Okay, now just relax.
掉了 吃藍莓嗎
Whoops... Blueberry?
不了
Pass.
出來吧 朱迪
Come on out, Judy.
拿著箱子
Take the case.
給牛局長
Get it to Bogo.
我不會把你留下的 絕對不會
I'm not gonna leave you behind. That's not happening.
我走不了
I can't walk.
我們會想到辦法的
Just... We'll think of something.
我們是同一隊的 朱迪
We're on the same team, Judy.
懷才不遇 不受重視
Underestimated, underappreciated.
你不覺得受夠了嗎
Aren't you sick of it?
食肉動物 或許他們是個高膽大
Predators. They may be strong and loud...
但食草動物數量是他們的十倍
but prey outnumber predators 10 to 1.
想想吧
Think of it.
百分之九十的人口
90% of the population...
聯合起來對抗共同的敵人
united against a common enemy.
我們將無堅不摧
We'll be unstoppable.
在那裏
Over there!
救命
Help!
你看 你應該乖乖待在
Well, you should have just stayed...
胡蘿蔔農場的 對吧
on the carrot farm, huh?
真是遺憾啊 我以前挺喜歡你的
It really is too bad. I... I did like you.
你想怎麼樣 殺了我嗎
What are you going to do? Kill me?
噢 當然不會啦
No, of course not.
他會
He is.
不 噢 尼克
No! Oh, Nick!
沒錯 警察 國家歷史博物館裏
Yes, police! There's a savage fox...
有一隻發狂的狐貍
in the Natural History Museum.
朱迪警官已倒下 請趕快來支援
Officer Hopps is down! Please, hurry.
不 尼克 別被控制啊
No. Nick, don't do this. Fight it.
噢 但他不能自控呀 不是嗎
Oh, but he can't help it, can he?
因為食肉動物生來就
Since preds are just biologically...
有可能野蠻化
predisposed to be savages.
天吶 想想明天的頭版新聞
Gosh. Think of the headline!
英雄警察被發狂狐貍殺害
Hero cop killed by savage fox.
這就是你要的 食草動物懼怕食肉動物
So that's it? Prey fears predator...
然後你繼續掌權
and you stay in power?
嗯 差不多吧
Yeah, pretty much.
不會管用的
It won't work!
恐懼總會管用
Fear always works.
即使要我毒射動物城裏
And I'll dart every predator...
所有的食肉動物也在所不惜
in Zootopia to keep it that way.
噢 尼克
Oh, Nick.
不
No.
再見啦 小兔子
Bye-bye, bunny.
血
Bleh...
鮮血噴涌 血流成河 然後一命嗚呼
Blood! Blood! Blood and death.
好啦 你演得太用力了
All right, you know, you're milking it.
還有 我想我們成功了 成功了
Besides, I think we got it. I think we got it.
我們得到證據啦 謝嘍 囉嗦羊
We got it up there, thank you, Yakety-yak!
你陳述得太完美了
You laid it all out beautifully.
什麼
What?
噢 你是在找血清嗎
Yeah... Oh, are you looking for the serum?
噢 血清在這兒呢
Well, it's right here.
你手裏的那把武器裏
What you've got in the weapon there?
裝的是藍莓 我家農場裏種的
Those are blueberries. From my family's farm.
很好吃喲 你應該嘗嘗
They are delicious. You should try some.
我嫁禍過獅子市長 我也能嫁禍你們
I framed Lionheart. I can frame you, too.
你口說無憑 我不會承認的
It's my word against yours.
噢 其實
Ooh, actually...
即使要我毒射動物城裏
And I'll dart every predator...
所有的食肉動物也在所不惜
in Zootopia to keep it that way.
你已經供認不諱了
...it's your word against yours.
這叫做智取 親愛的 崩
It's called a hustle, sweetheart. Boom.
前任羊市長被捕入獄
近期困擾動物城的動物襲擊事件
Former mayor Dawn Bellwether is behind bars today...
幕後黑手前任市長道恩·領頭羊
guilty of masterminding the savage attacks...
今日被捕入獄
that have plagued Zootopia of late.
她的前任 裏奧多·獅子心
Her predecessor, Leodore Lionheart...
獅子市長打破沉默
否認知情她的陰謀
denies any knowledge of her plot...
聲稱他只是為了保護城市
claiming he was just trying to protect the city.
我囚禁那些動物是錯誤的嗎
Did I falsely imprison those animals?
是的 這不應該
Well, yes. Yes, I did.
這種做法就是典型的
It was a classic "Doing the wrong thing...
「出於好心 做了壞事」
"For the right reason" Kind of a deal.
此外 醫生宣稱
In related news, doctors say...
午夜嚎叫治療證實有效
午夜嚎叫解毒劑在治療
the Night Howler antidote is proving effective...
受害食肉動物上 證實有效
in rehabilitating the afflicted predators.
埃米特
Emmitt.
噢 埃米特
Oh, Emmitt.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我小的時候
When I was a kid...
我以為動物城是個完美的地方
...L thought Zootopia was this perfect place.
以為大家都能和睦相處 每個人皆有無限可能
Where everyone got along and anyone could be anything.
結果發現
Turns out...
現實生活總比貼紙上的口號
real life's a little bit more complicated...
要複雜得多
than a slogan on a bumper sticker.
現實生活很糟糕
Real life is messy.
我們都有自己的局限 我們都會犯錯
We all have limitations. We all make mistakes.
所以 樂觀地說
Which means, hey, glass half-full...
我們都有很多共同之處
we all have a lot in common.
我們越努力去瞭解彼此
And the more we try to understand one another...
就越會發現彼此的與眾不同
the more exceptional each of us will be.
但我們總得一試
But we have to try.
所以 不管你是什麼動物
So, no matter what type of animal you are...
從最大只的大象
from the biggest elephant...
到我們的第一隻狐貍
to our first fox...
我請求你們 努力嘗試
I implore you... Try.
讓這個世界變得更美好
Try to make the world a better place.
從心審視自己
Look inside yourself...
並認識到 改變
and recognize that change...
需要從你做起
starts with you.
從我做起
It starts with me.
從我們身邊做起
It starts with all of us.
好了好了 閉嘴
All right. All right, enough! Shut it!
我們今早來了些新成員
We have some new recruits with us this morning...
包括我們的第一隻狐貍
including our first fox.
誰在乎呢
Who cares?
哈 長官 你應該給自己準備好
Huh, you should have your own line...
一份鼓舞人心的發言稿
of inspirational greeting cards, sir.
閉上你的嘴 王爾德
Shut your mouth, Wilde.
分配任務
Assignments.
灰熊佐利 尖牙狼 德爾加多警官
Officers Grizzoli, Fangmeyer, Delgato...
冰原鎮特警隊
Tundratown SWAT.
熊咆洛 河馬斯 狼法德
Snarlov, Higgins, Wolfard...
臥底行動
undercover.
霍普斯 王爾德
Hopps, Wilde.
交通協管
Parking duty.
解散
Dismissed.
開個玩笑啦
Just kidding!
我們收到警報 大草原區中心
We have reports of a street racer...
出現一名飆車黨
tearing up Savannah Central.
找到他 抓回來
Find him, shut him down.
是所有兔子車技都這麼爛
So, are all rabbits bad drivers...
還是只有你
or is it just you?
噢 抱歉
Oops. Sorry.
狡猾兔子
Sly bunny.
蠢笨狐貍
Dumb fox.
你知道你是愛我的
You know you love me.
我知道嗎
Do I know that?
對 沒錯 我知道
Yes. Yes, I do.
先生 你時速高達115英里
Sir, you were going 115 miles per hour.
你最好有個好借口
I hope you have a good explanation.
閃電
Flash?
閃電閃電 瞬息萬變
Flash? Hundred yard dash?
尼克
Nick.
晚上好 動物城
Good evening, Zootopia!
大家一起來 舉起你們的爪
Come on, everybody, put your paws up!
讓我看到你們的爪
Put your paws in the air. Come on!
來吧
Come on!
和我一起 尾巴擺起來
Shake your tails with me. Come on!
耶
Yeah!